


  
  
 
  
   
    GLORY DAYS
    a new musical by nick blaemire
     &amp; james gardiner
   
   
    
     Broadway
    
   
   
    04/05/08
    
    
     
     Please address inquiries to:
     William Craver
     Paradigm New York
     360 Park Avenue South, 16th Floor
     New York, New York 10010
     wcraver@paradigmagency.com
     (212) 897-6400
    
    
   
   

 
  
   GLORY DAYS
   A New Musical
   Music and Lyrics by Nick Blaemire 
   Book by James Gardiner
  
 
(A night in May. A high school football field. WILLIAM LEVINSON, 18, enters wearing a backpack and carrying a small notebook. He walks out to the center of the field)
 
MY THREE BEST FRIENDS

WILL
LOOK AT THIS FIELD
LOOK AT THIS PERFECT FIELD
THE POSSIBILITIES ARE ENDLESS HERE

JUST WHITE LINES
NO BOUNDARIES TO HOLD US HERE
EXCEPT FOR TIME
AND SO MUCH HISTORY
IMAGINE WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE
ALL THE STORIES
GAMES THAT HAVE BEEN WON
AND FRIENDS HAVING FUN
COMING BACK FOR ONE PERFECT NIGHT

RIGHT HERE

(WILL sets his backpack down on the player's bench.)

THIS IS THE STORY OF FOUR BEST FRIENDS
WHEN WE'RE IN ONE PLACE THE NIGHT NEVER ENDS
WE TALK ABOUT THINGS THAT MATTER, AND THEN
IN THE SAME BREATH ACT LIKE WE'RE TEN
 AND THEN DO IT ALL OVER AGAIN


WE'RE FROM - JUST IMAGINE THIS KIND OF TOWN
WHERE THE POPULAR CLIQUE KEEPS YOU DOWN
IF YOU CAN'T PUT ON PADS AND MAKE CAVEMAN SOUNDS
AS YOU KNOCK SMALLER KIDS THAN YOU TO THE GROUND
 DOESN'T THAT SOUND FUN TO BE AROUND?

WE WERE NEVER BIG ENOUGH OR FAST ENOUGH
TO KEEP UP WITH ALL OF THEM

BUT WE WERE ALWAYS SMART ENOUGH AND QUICK ENOUGH 
TO KNOW WE'D BE BETTER IN THE END
THAN THE SENIORS FROM THE FOOTBALL TEAM
WHO WOULDN'T LET US PLAY
WE COULDN'T CATCH OR RUN AS FAST
SO THEY TOLD US WE WERE GAY
THEY TRIED TO MAKE US WORSHIP THEM
BUT WE LIKED THINGS OUR WAY
   JUST ME AND MY THREE BEST FRIENDS


(WILL pulls his notebook out of his backpack)
 
SKIP IS THE CYNIC AND JACK'S THE VOICE OF REASON
AND ANDY'S THE REASON THAT SKIP IS A CYNIC
WE'RE BICKERING BROTHERS, IT'S SICK
IT'S LIKE IF OIL AND WATER COULD MIX
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT US THAT JUST CLICKS

CUZ I AM THE GLUE THAT HOLDS US TOGETHER

OBSERVER, INVENTOR, AND SOLE DOCUMENTOR
CONSTANTLY WATCHING, THE CONSTANT INCENTIVE 
TO KEEP MOVING FORWARD, AND ALWAYS REMEMBER
WHERE WE STARTED FROM, AND HOW FAR WE'VE COME
SINCE THE DAYS WHEN WE HAD NO ONE
BUT WE FORMED THIS PERFECT UNION
AND AN ERA HAD BEGUN
WE GET THIS LIFE SO DIFFERENTLY
THEN ANYONE OUR AGE CHOOSES TO SEE

ME AND MY THREE BEST FRIENDS
 
(WILL begins to write) 
 
YOUR BEST FRIENDS OPEN UP YOUR MIND
TO PARTS OF YOU YOU COULDN'T FIND
THEY SAVED MY LIFE FRESHMAN YEAR
AND I THANK THEM EVERY DAY RIGHT HERE


WE'VE BEEN AWAY FOR WAY TOO LONG
AND ALL THAT TIME ALONE FELT WRONG
  CAUSE WE WILL ALWAYS BELONG RIGHT HERE

(WILL slams his notebook shut and tosses it under the bench) 

AND WE'RE COMING BACK TONIGHT
TO REMEMBER WHAT WE WERE LIKE

AND PICK UP RIGHT WHERE WE LET GO
ALMOST A YEAR AGO

I KNOW THIS STORY SO WELL
AND IT IS MINE TO TELL
BECAUSE IT IS HAPPENING...TO ME
YEA ME AND MY THREE 
ME AND MY THREE
ME AND MY THREE

 BEST FRIENDS

(SKIP THOMAS, 19, enters without WILL noticing.)

SKIP
Who're you talking to...?

WILL
SKIP!! (startled) HEY!!!


SKIP
HEYYY buddy!

(WILL and SKIP hug)

WILL
It's SO good to see you man!

SKIP
You too!


WILL
You look great!

SKIP
You look... the same.

WILL
What!? Come on! I got new sneakers!

SKIP

I see that.

WILL
(showing off his new Converse All Stars) They're sexy, right?

SKIP
Oh yea. Very. Very hip.

WILL

 I know.

(SKIP laughs at WILL)

What? Okay jerk, what's up with your hair?
 
SKIP
You like? I'm letting nature do its thing.

WILL

(amused) You look like a girl.

SKIP
Oh, you wanna start already? Cause we can go dickcheese.

(SKIP playfully slaps WILL's ass) 



  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
  
  
SKIP
Let's go! Who's a girl now? Huh?

WILL
I'm joking! No. Okay, okay!

  

WILL
HEY, look, if you don't stop I'm not telling you what we're doing tonight!

SKIP
(stops) What we're doing? I thought this was it.


WILL
 Nope. I've got a plan. Tell me -
 
ARE YOU READY

WILL
ARE YOU READY FOR TONIGHT?

SKIP

 What?
 
WILL
ARE YOU READY TO MAKE HISTORY? 
RIGHT HERE ON THIS FOOTBALL FIELD 
YOU AND ME 
AND TWO OTHER GUYS 
WHO COULD SHOW UP AT ANY TIME 

WHEN EVER THEY DO GET HERE, I'M
HOPING YOU'RE READY

SKIP
What are we doing?

WILL
 I can't tell you that.
 

SKIP
 Why not?
 
WILL
(coyly) Cause... I don't know if I trust you.

SKIP
Just tell me!


WILL
Not yet!
WHEN THE TIMING IS RIGHT
WE ALL WILL BE HERE FINALLY
AND WHEN WE ARE, YOU'LL FINALLY SEE
"WHAT THIS HIGH SCHOOL MEANS TO ME"

SKIP
HOW 'BOUT A HINT?


WILL
HOW 'BOUT WE WAIT FOR ALL THE GUYS

SKIP
I'LL ACT LIKE I'M STILL SURPRISED

WILL
 FINE. DO YOU LIKE WATER RIDES?


SKIP
 LIKE SLIP N' SLIDES?

WILL
Yes!

SKIP
Really?

WILL

No.

SKIP
Come on!

WILL
DON'T EVEN TRY TO GUESS
YOU WONT BE ABLE TO
CAUSE WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
 IS GONNA DUMBFOUND EVEN YOU

 
(ANDY SCOTT, 19, and JACK MOYER, 19, enter bickering.)

ANDY
Oh pleeease dude, Batman is so much cooler. He's got all those gadgets and shit-
 
JACK
 So!? Superman could pick up an entire planet and drop it on Batman.
 

ANDY
Yeah, but can he stop a Batarang?

JACK
He can travel at the speed of light, Andy. You don't think he can get away from a Batarang?

ANDY
Will, help me out here. Batman v. Superman. Who wins?

WILL

 Superman.
 
ANDY
(to WILL) Fuck that!

WILL
Jaaaack!


JACK
Wiiill! What up Holmes!?

WILL
What up Skillet!?

ANDY
 (sees SKIP) Hey, who's the hippie? 

 
SKIP
 Nice to see you too!

(Without missing a beat, ANDY tries to get SKIP's opinion on the whole Batman vs. Superman debate.) 
  
WILL
 (to JACK) ARE YOU READY FOR TONIGHT?


JACK
 CAN YOU BELIEVE WE'RE BACK OUT HERE?
 
WILL
IT HAS BEEN THE LONGEST YEAR!

JACK
 (looking around) I GOTTA SAY IT'S PRETTY WEIRD


WILL
 HOW WAS LIFE AT SCHOOL?

JACK
 PROBABLY THE SAME AS YOU

WILL
 THERE IS NO WAY THAT'S TRUE UNLESS YOU ROOMED WITH ANDY TOO.


SKIP
(to ANDY) Drop it - 

ANDY
HOW THE HELL COULD YOU THINK THAT BATMAN
WOULD LOSE A BATTLE TO A GUY IN TIGHTS?
HAVEN'T YOU SEEN THOSE GAY RED UNDIES
 HE WEARS OUTSIDE OF HIS PANTS?

 
SKIP
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY YOU'D EVER BEGIN
TO ARGUE WITH ME, WHEN YOU KNOW YOU'LL NEVER WIN 
 BATMAN IS HUMAN AND SUPERMAN'S NOT
 SO WHO'S GONNA DIE IF ONE OF THEM GETS SHOT?

ANDY

What's your point?

WILL
 Sooo... ARE WE READY FOR TONIGHT?

SKIP
 WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?

WILL

 HAVE I EVER STEERED YOU WRONG?

SKIP
 I DUNNO. IT'S BEEN SO LONG.
 
WILL
JUST GET READY FOR TONIGHT
AND WHAT A NIGHT IT'S GONNA BE

 YOU AND YOU AND YOU AND ME
 
ALL
 FINALLY...

WILL
 BACK TOGETHER


JACK
 I'VE MISSED YOU GUYS

ANDY (to JACK)
 YOU ONLY LIKE SUPERMAN CAUSE HE FLIES
 
WILL

 NOW ARE YOU READY FOR
 
ALL GIYS
READY
FOR TONIGHT...
RIGHT
HERE!!

(WILL runs over to his backpack)


SKIP
Where have you guys been?

JACK
(indicating ANDY) Ask slobbers over here, I was waiting outside his house for like 10 minutes!

ANDY
I said I was sorry! I'm sorry!


SKIP
Slobbers? What was he doing?

JACK
He was passed out in the living room watching Ella Enchanted.

ANDY
I was not!


JACK
Slobbering all over the sofa.

ANDY
Whatever man! My sister was watching it.

SKIP
 Oh yeaaah, how's she doing?


(JACK laughs)

ANDY
(to SKIP) Don't start - 

SKIP
What!? I'm not allowed to ask!

ANDY

(suspicious) She's fine.

SKIP
That's good. (beat) Does she still ask about me?

ANDY
She's twelve years old!


JACK
Hey, whatever floats your boat, right?

ANDY
(to JACK) MY sister is not allowed to float anyone's boat!


SKIP
Aww, you're no fun.

JACK
But your sister is!

SKIP and JACK
 OHHHHHHH!! (raspberry)


(SKIP and JACK slap high five)

ANDY
(grabbing at SKIP and JACK) You're both dead! Come here!

SKIP
What? Take it as a compliment, you're sister's banging!

JACK

Yeah, you've got good genes!

ANDY
I swear to God -

WILL
All right guys! Come on! Hey! HEY!

(WILL throws his arms around ANDY to hold him back.)

(to ANDY) Chill! Look, we've got important business to take care of -


(ANDY stops struggling and WILL releases him.)

ANDY
(to SKIP) I got you later!

SKIP
Oh yeah?

JACK

Really?

ANDY
Yeah, I do!

WILL
(scolding) Okay, enough! Here. Read.

(WILL hands ANDY a newspaper clipping)


ANDY
What is this?

WILL
 Just read!

(ANDY takes a look at the paper. Clears his throat and reads)

ANDY

(reading) "Come one, come all to the First Annual Fighting Beavers Alumni Football Game." What!? FIGHTING Beavers? When did they change that shit?

WILL
Apparently they didn't think the beaver was intimidating enough on its own.

ANDY
But that makes no sense. Beavers aren't violent. They're gentle woodland creatures.

WILL

Keep reading!

ANDY
Okay! (reading) "On Saturday May 20th watch our very own Fighting Beavers"... (aside) mmmGAY! ... "take on the Varsity Alumni in what promises to be a real treat. All Alumni are invited to attend."

SKIP
Wow, you read that really well! 


ANDY
Shut up! (to WILL) What the hell is this?

WILL
 This, my friend, is inspiration.

(WILL takes the paper from ANDY and walks back towards the player's bench)


ANDY
What?

SKIP
 Oh no....

(WILL steps up on the player's bench as if it were his own personal soapbox)

WILL

Do you guys realize what this means? Tomorrow afternoon. On this field, we're gonna have...  (pointing to Andy) can I get a drum roll please? 

ANDY
Totes! (ANDY begins drum roll) 

WILL
Matt Hoffman, Chris Peterson, Eric Spencer, Danny Barwick -


JACK
No shit!?

WILL
Yes shit! The whole lot of em. And at exactly 1:30, while they're lining up for the opening kick, they're going to witness... no scratch that... EXPERIENCE a miracle.

JACK
Is it Jesus?
  
WILL
No. Better. You see that box?

(WILL points to a small weather box situated near the players bench)


  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
  
  
ANDY
Yup.

JACK
Yeah.


WILL
Skip?

SKIP
Uh-huh. Box. Got it.

WILL
That box contains the timer to the school's brand new... state of the art... sprinkler system. (reaches into his pocket and pulls out a key) And this, my friends, is the key.


(WILL tosses the key to ANDY)

ANDY
(gets it) Fucking genius!

JACK
I don't get it.

ANDY

(amazed. To WILL) We're gonna soak the bastards!

JACK
Why?

ANDY
Cause it's FUNNY!


WILL
No, it's payback. For every time we got walked on or treated like we didn't matter.  We've been waiting for this moment for five years and now this is our chance to finally say something to them. All we have to do is reset the timer.

ANDY
Blown! My mind is officially blown.

(SKIP takes the key from ANDY)

SKIP
How did you even get this?


WILL
I have my sources.

JACK
Who?

WILL
I know people. 

JACK

No you don't.

WILL
Look, it doesn't matter how I got it! The fact is I got it! So come on let's do this! (walks to box)

ANDY
Why're you being so weird?

WILL
I'm not. It's just not important.


JACK
Will, you can't do that!

ANDY
Yeah, you have to tell us! Come on, we're not gonna say anything!

WILL
(a strained, pregnant beat) Hannah Gillman.


ANDY
HORSEFACE!?

SKIP
Who?

WILL
(to ANDY) Exactly why I didn't want to tell you!


ANDY
You don't remember Hannah!? Sophomore? Redhead? She's the janitor's niece. Kinda ... horsefaced!

WILL
Andy - 

ANDY
What!? 

WILL

Don't call her that!

ANDY
I'm creating a visual. 

JACK
(to WILL) Wait, is this the girl who asked you to homecoming, but you said no for religious reasons? 

ANDY

That's the one!

SKIP
Oh, HER! (beat) Wow.

JACK
Why'd she give it to you?

WILL

(a slight hesitation) Cause she was being nice.

ANDY
(joking) Yeah right! What'd you do, take her out on a date?

WILL
(caught off guard) No, it wasn't a - (stops mid sentence. Catches himself)


ANDY
What?

WILL
Huh?

ANDY
It wasn't a what?


WILL
What?

ANDY
Oh sweet Lord Jesus NO! (beat) You DID!

WILL
No I - No. (pause) It wasn't a date -


ANDY
(hardly controlling himself) Then what was it?

WILL
We just went out to eat. - 

ANDY
To EAT!? You mean to GRAZE! 


WILL
Andy - 

SKIP
What'd you do, let her gnaw on your carrot? 

ANDY
OHHH!!! Nice!

WILL

You guys are jerks, you know that?

ANDY
Ah come on man. We're just playing! Look, I'm really proud of you! She's a catch.

JACK
Definitely.

WILL
She's not a catch and you know it! 


ANDY
Why? 

WILL
Cause she's...

ANDY
 ...ugly? That's fucked up Will.


(SKIP and JACK laugh at this)

WILL
I didn't say that. You're the one calling her that!

ANDY
All I'm saying is...she's a sure thing. (putting his arm around WILL) And Will, buddy, you need to start taking advantage of these opportunities. Cause let's be honest, you didn't really get any this year.

WILL

(pushing ANDY away) Just cuz I didn't want any of the diseased skanks that you and your frat brothers hooked up with doesn't mean I didn't get any.

ANDY
What are you talking about? Those girls were prime real estate!
 
SKIP
Woah, woah, woah. I'm sorry. You joined a frat? 

ANDY

(proudly) Hells yeah manio! Delta Kai Epsilon! Deke Men - Class of 2010 baby

SKIP
Oh God. 

WILL
I know. Of all things. (points to ANDY) HUGE hypocrite!


ANDY
ME? WHY!?

WILL
Cause it goes against everything we stand for.

SKIP
And it's just lame.

ANDY

You're lame!

JACK
Isn't that kinda like buying your friends?

ANDY
(offended) No! It's about a brotherhood. A fellowship! A bond!

WILL

That you pay for.

ANDY
Whatever man, all I know is I was getting some high quality poon this year while you were sitting alone in the room jerkin the gherkin! 

WILL
I was not.

ANDY
Oh really? Why don't you tell Jack and Skip how many girls you boofed?


WILL
They don't care. Now can we just set off these-

SKIP
I'm kind of interested.

JACK
Me too.

ANDY

Well I'll tell you! The answer is zero. None! Nada! He is incapable of getting ass.
 
WILL
That's not true.
										
ANDY
Uh, okay then. How many?


WILL
I don't know... like... probably... 15.
 
SKIP
(amazed) Really?

WILL
Yeah really... maybe even 20.

  
  
  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
  

JACK
Wow man, good for you!

SKIP
Yeah, I never would have thought -

ANDY
 Bullshit!! (to SKIP and JACK) He's lying!

 
WILL
I am not!

ANDY
(to SKIP and JACK) I've been with him the whole year. He hasn't even talked to 15 girls.

WILL
You don't have to talk to 'em when you're doing it.


SKIP
He's got a point! 

ANDY
 You're so full of shit.
 
WILL
 Don't be hurt.

 
ANDY
 I'm not!
 
WE'VE GOT GIRLS

ANDY
D'YOU EVER WONDER WHERE THE FEMALES GO
WHEN YOU'RE OUT AT THE BAR AND REALIZE YOU'RE FLYING SOLO

TOO BAD FOR YOU BECAUSE THEY'RE HERE WITH ME
WAITING IN LINE UNTIL WE MAMBO HORIZONTALLY

WILL
D'YOU EVER WONDER WHERE HE GETS THIS SHIT
OR IF ANY OF THE SKANKS THAT HE BANGS BELIEVE A WORD OF IT?
HE ISN'T ANYBODY'S MR. RIGHT
 I'M THE ONE THE LADIES WANT FOR MORE THAN JUST A NIGHT


ANDY
DON'T LISTEN TO A WORD HE SAYS
 HE HASN'T BEEN KISSED SINCE TRUTH OR DARE

WILL
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT'S TRUE
WHEN IM WITH GIRLS I DON'T THINK YOU'RE THERE
I SAY WHAT THEY WANNA HEAR

AND YOU DON'T KNOW CUZ YOU DON'T CARE

 IVE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS

ANDY
What??

WILL
 IVE FIGURED EM OUT AND GOT EM UP AGAINST THE WALL



ANDY
YOU'VE GOT NOTHING AT ALL
YOU'RE MAKING THIS UP!
YOU'D HAVE TO HIDE IN A WOMEN'S BATHROOM STALL
 TO GET A GIRL NEAR YOUR BALLS

ANDY
Don't lie Will, it makes you look bad.


WILL
Hey, I'm not saying I'm the best looking guy around. I never used to get any, but things change, Andy. Things change. 

WILL
 IN HIGH SCHOOL, GIRLS WERE OUT OF MY LEAGUE AND I KNEW IT

JACK
I'm glad you knew it!


WILL
 ONE AWKWARD GLANCE OR THEY'D SEE ME DANCE AND I BLEW IT

SKIP
What about Horseface?

WILL
 BUT COLLEGE GIRLS ARE MUCH MORE MY STYLE
   

ANDY
 CUZ THEY'RE JEWISH

WILL
- Oh God.

ANDY
 ALL THEY DO IS TURN YOU AND YOUR JEW BALLS BLUISH


WILL
IT'S TOO BAD HE'S AN IDIOT
HE MIGHT GET SOME IF HE GOT TO CLASS

ANDY
I NEVER NEEDED IT
 I KNOW MY SHIT AND CAN STILL KICK YOUR ASS

ANDY and WILL

YOU ARE THE OPPOSITE OF ME
IM MORE THAN HAPPY TO AGREE

SKIP
Jesus, you guys haven't changed at all.

ANDY
You're right, Will's still a lying Jew!

WILL

HALF JEW!

ANDY
Half Jew, whole Jew, it's all the same. You're still a virgin.

SKIP
You guys are ridiculous.

JACK
Yea, don't you wanna find something normal? Like love?


WILL (ANDY "poontang's" throughout)
OF COURSE WE WANT TO BE IN LOVE
AND WE'RE LOOKING FOR ROMANCE
BUT TIL WE FIND THAT LONESOME DOVE

ANDY and WILL
WE'LL JUST GET INTO THEIR PAAAAANTS!! 
WE'VE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS


THEY'RE LOOKIN FOR LOVE BUT THAT'S NOT WHAT WE'RE MAKIN AT ALL
WE'VE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS AND WE'RE HOLDIN ON
IT'S TIME FOR EVERY GIRL TO BE GRABBED
BY THE BALLS!

ANDY
 HOW DO YOU WIN A PLAYOFF RACE?

WILL

 BY THE BALLS!

ANDY
 AND WHERE DO WE LIKE A PRETTY GIRL'S FACE?

WILL
BY THE BALLS!

ANDY

AND WHERE DO WE HAVE JACK'S MOM!

WILL
OHHHHHH!

JACK
Fuck you guys!

WILL and ANDY
 BY THE BALLS!


(JACK tackles ANDY. Playful fighting.)

JACK
(punches ANDY) Jerk! (to WILL) I can't believe you lived with him for a whole year.

WILL
It was hard sometimes, he never showers.


ANDY
Shut up dude!

WILL
Maybe once a week.

ANDY
Whatever, I was a great roommate.


JACK
I wouldn't want to live with you.

ANDY
Why not!? We coulda been bunk buddies! 

WILL
What if the four of us had all gone to the same school?

ANDY

That woulda been tight! The four of us in a suite, trading bitches like Pokemon cards!

JACK
Sorry for ruining your dream.

WILL
I mean, just think of all the stuff we could've pulled on a college campus. 

SKIP
You mean stupid pranks like this one?


WILL
What are you talking about? This is gonna be epic! We're gonna go down in history for this.

SKIP
With who? No one's even gonna know we did it!

WILL
Um, we'll know.

ANDY

(to SKIP) What is your problem, Debbie Downer?

SKIP
Excuse me?

ANDY
You. Anytime there's any risk involved you look like you're gonna pee yourself!

SKIP

No I don't!

WILL
Yes you do! 

ANDY
What about that time we took out your Dad's Jeep?
 
SKIP
That was my idea!


ANDY
Yeah, but you were so nervous. "I dunno guys, maybe we should abort..."

JACK
To be fair, his dad is pretty frightening.

ANDY
Yea, but who says abort?

SKIP

My dad's in the military, jackass!

ANDY
Yeah, but you're not! No one said you had to speak like a douchebag!

WILL
Andy, will you shut up for a second! 

ARE YOU READY REPRISE


WILL
ARE WE READY FOR TONIGHT?

SKIP
AREN'T WE ALREADY HERE?

ANDY
DID ANYBODY GET THE BEER?

WILL

WE'LL DRINK IT WHEN WE'RE IN THE CLEAR
SO GET READY FOR TONIGHT
AND WHAT A NIGHT ITS GONNA BE
YOU AND YOU AND YOU AND ME

(The boys move over to the box)

ALL
FINALLY...


(WILL turns the key, but -)

WILL
Shit!

ANDY
What?

WILL
It won't open.


ANDY
Yes it will. 

WILL
No, actually, it won't.

ANDY
Get outta the way! You don't know how to turn a friggin key. 

(ANDY pushes WILL out of the way)


Here. See you gotta turn it to the left you dil-

(ANDY tries to turn the key, but the lock won't budge)
You gotta turn it to the -

(ANDY tries again, but the lock still won't budge)
You gotta - 

WILL
Yes?

 
ANDY
 Dammit!!

WILL
 See?
 
ANDY

(to WILL) You got the wrong key!

WILL
I got the wrong key!? This is what she gave me. 

ANDY
God damn it HORSEFACE HANNAH! 

WILL

Andy -

ANDY
You got scammed by Mr. Ed! 

WILL
She probably just got em mixed up.

JACK
Can you call her?


WILL
What? No!

ANDY
Why not?

WILL
You call her!

ANDY

Why the hell would I call her? She's your girlfriend!

WILL
She is not, shut up!

ANDY
 Look, stop being a pussy. (ANDY takes out his phone) If she got em mixed up then she can bring over the right one-


(ANDY tosses his phone to WILL)

WILL
No, its gonna give her the wrong idea.

(WILL tosses the phone back to ANDY)

ANDY
 Just tell her to put down the oats and get over here-


(ANDY tosses the phone to WILL)

WILL
 I'm not doing it!
 
(WILL tosses the phone back to ANDY)

ANDY
Well I guess we can't do the prank then.


(ANDY tosses the phone to WILL)

WILL
 Andy!

(WILL tosses the phone to ANDY. SKIP catches it)

SKIP
Jesus Christ, who cares!?


WILL
What do you mean who cares? 

ANDY
What are we supposed to do now?

SKIP
Why don't we try hanging out for a change? You ever think of that?

ANDY

We are.

SKIP
No, this is not hanging out. You guys wanna play Inspector Gadget or whatever, but I'd rather just sit here and drink some beers. Why do we have to DO something to make the night memorable? I haven't seen you guys in almost a year. We're finally together in the same place. Isn't that enough? 

WILL
(beat) Sorry.


SKIP
 Think about it. We don't have to associate ourselves with this place ever again, so why do you wanna come back and pull some stupid prank? We're past that.
 
WILL
It's not stupid! 

JACK
It's pretty stupid.


WILL
Jack!?

JACK
Sorry, it is.

WILL
Guys! Andy? Help me out here.

ANDY

I mean, yeah, I still think it'd be funny as shit. 

WILL
And it sends a message. (the boys are unconvinced) It does!

SKIP
What message is that?

WILL

That we deserve respect.

SKIP
From who?

WILL
From them!

SKIP
Oh that makes a ton of sense, Will. (beat) You really think they're gonna start respecting us for setting off sprinklers during their little charity football game?


WILL
It's not about that!

SKIP
Then what's it -

JACK
Skip, if he wants to do it, let him do it.

WILL

No, I want ALL of us to do it! Come on, don't you think they deserve it!

SKIP
Will it was five years ago!

WILL
So!? It still happened! And all because we didn't make their precious little team -

SKIP

Here we go. 

WILL
No! They're the reason that we're friends. So why not, you know, celebrate that by giving them the fuck you that they deserve?

SKIP
But Will, they're not gonna care. They never did, so why would they start now? 

WILL
 Then maybe, it's not about them! Maybe it's about us!


RIGHT HERE

WILL
WHEN YOU WERE YOUNG
DIDN'T YOU HAVE DREAMS THAT YOU LET GO OF
CUZ SOMEBODY TOLD YOU THAT YOU WEREN'T ALLOWED TO DREAM
THE WAY YOU DO
 JUST CUZ YOU WERE DIFFERENT


    LIKE
WHEN I WAS 12 
I BOUGHT MYSELF SOME LA LIGHTS
REMEMBER, THOSE SHOES THAT YOU COULD SEE AT NIGHT
CUZ BRIAN NOONAN RULED AND HE WORE THEM TO SCHOOL 
AND I HATED HIM
BUT I WANTED TO BE COOL 


ANDY
OR 
IN 7TH GRADE
I STARTED SAYING "CHILLIN BRO"
WHAT IT MEANS I STILL DON'T KNOW
BUT COLIN SPENCER SAID THEY ALL KNEW WHAT IT MEANT
AND IF I DIDN'T 
I'D LOOK LIKE A TOOL


WILL
THAT'S WHAT I USED TO THINK
RIGHT WHEN I WAS ON THE BRINK
OF BEING JUST ANOTHER KINK IN THEIR SOCIAL REGIME
BUT MY LIFE GOT TURNED AROUND
 WHEN I FOUND I GOT CUT FROM THEIR FOOTBALL TEAM

RIGHT HERE WAS THE FIRST PLACE I FELT HOME
WITH NO FEAR OF MY LIFE SPENT ALL ALONE 

IT WAS CLEAR UNDER THESE ELECTRIC STARS 
THAT NO MATTER WHAT THEY SAID FROM OVER THERE 
THIS FIELD WAS OURS 
RIGHT HERE 

SKIP
(sarcastic) Well that's touching.

WILL

Come on man, you used to love this stuff.

SKIP
Used to! I'd like to think I've changed a little since I left this place.

WILL
No, this place made us who we are! 

SKIP

DID YOU THINK
YOU'D NEVER CHANGE?
YOU'D JUST STAY IN SOME PERFECT, STRANGE YEARBOOK MOMENT
BUT YOU MOVED AWAY
 AND YOU CAN PRAY THAT THEY'LL STAY
BUT THE GOOD OLD DAYS SAY GOODBYE
 AND SORRY, YOU ARE DIFFERENT



  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   	
  
  
WILL
NO! CUZ WE'RE STILL YOUNG
AND THOUGH YOU MAY HAVE TRIED
TO RID OUR LIVES
OF THE COOL PEOPLE'S BULLSHIT
THE BRUISES TO PROVE THAT IT
STUNG ARE STILL HERE
CAUSE WE'RE STILL DIFFERENT


ANDY
NO WE'RE STILL YOUNG
YEAH
WHAT HE SAID
WE'RE STILL DIFFERENT

JACK
OH PLEASE, JUST LET IT BE
CUZ NO ONE'S MAKING SENSE RIGHT NOW

YES WE CHANGE AND AREN'T SURE HOW 
BUT I DON'T CARE WHAT IT TOOK TO GET ME TO HERE FROM THERE
I MAY BE DIFFERENT
BUT IM STILL ME I SWEAR

WILL
I KNOW, YOU'RE RIGHT, BUT SO AM I
WE CAN CHANGE, BUT CAN'T DENY
WE'LL ALWAYS BE THE GUYS WE WERE WHEN WE MET


ANDY and WILL
AND BACK WHEN WE BEGAN IT
WE DIDN'T PLAN IT 
 BUT WE CAN'T FORGET

RIGHT HERE WAS THE FIRST PLACE YOU FELT HOME
WITH NO FEAR OF A LIFE SPENT ALL ALONE
CUZ ITS CLEAR UNDER THESE ELECTRIC STARS, THAT


JACK, ANDY and WILL
NO MATTER WHAT YOU SAY FROM OVER THERE

WILL
THIS IS OURS

JACK, WILL and ANDY
 RIGHT??


    SKIP (WITH THE GUYS BEHIND HIM)
HERE WAS THE FIRST PLACE I FELT HOME
WITH NO FEAR OF MY LIFE SPENT ALL ALONE
CUZ ITS CLEAR UNDER THESE ELECTRIC STARS

ALL THE GUYS
IT ONLY MATTERS WHAT YOU SEE
RIGHT HERE 

IS A BETTER PLACE THAN HOME
CUZ ITS CLEAR THAT WE'LL NEVER BE ALONE
AND THIS YEAR UNDER THESE ELECTRIC STARS
NO MATTER WHAT YOU SAY FROM OVER THERE
WE'LL STILL BE
RIGHT HERE

WILL
All right let's do this!!


ANDY
HELLS YEAH!

JACK
YEAH!!

SKIP
 Hold on, guys! How are we getting into this box?


(Silence. ANDY, JACK, and SKIP look at WILL)

ANDY
Will?

WILL
 (sigh) Fine.  I'll call her.


(WILL walks over to his backpack)

ANDY
That's my boy. Take one for the team!

WILL
I'm always taking one for the team.

(WILL pulls out his cell phone. The guys crowd around him)

Back up!


ANDY
You got her on speed dial?

WILL
(to Andy) Shut-up. Seriously. (into the phone) Hi, Hannah? 

ANDY

 Neiiiiiiiigh! (like a horse)

(WILL moves away from the guys.)

WILL
(glares at ANDY) It's Will! Hi. I'm fine. Listen, I'm calling because that key you gave me doesn't actually work. So...yeah. I was just wondering if there was any possibility - (beat) Oh, really!? No, that would be amazing, thank you!


ANDY
What'd she say?!

WILL
Uh... Friday? I... ummm (looking to the guys for help) See, the thing is, I can't hang out Friday cuz... I've got a... family reunion.

(SKIP, ANDY and JACK start laughing)


ANDY
WHAT?!

WILL
 (to ANDY) Shut up shut up shut up! (to HORSEFACE) Yeah, yeah, we're going out of town for like...a week. I would LOVE to hang out with you, but, I have to go cuz I'd be like the only one not there so, you know, gotta take one for the team.


(WILL glares at the guys, who are impressed)

THE BOYS
OOOOOOHHHHH!

WILL
 Anyways, let me know if you find anything tonight, okay? Great thanks you're the best, bye!
 
(WILL hangs up the phone)


SKIP
(sarcastic) You're the best?

WILL
(frustrated) Shut-up.

ANDY

You are the worst liar EVER!

WILL
Yeah, well you guys didn't help! Now I'm gonna have to go into hiding for like a week! (under his breath) Fuckin' bullshit. 

JACK
What'd she say?

WILL

She's babysitting right now, she's going to look and see what she can find. She said she'd call me back.

SKIP
So we're just waiting?

WILL
I guess so.

ANDY
 Dammit!


(Silence)

JACK
I feel like we should have brought a board game or something. 

ANDY
Like Jenga!?

WILL
Jenga's not a board game!


JACK
I was thinking more along the lines of like Monopoly.

ANDY
I hate Monopoly.

SKIP
You would.

ANDY

What is that supposed to mean?

SKIP
You're just not a Monopoly kinda guy. 

ANDY
Yea, cuz I hate it.

SKIP
No, I think it's more that you don't get it.


ANDY
Oh I get it.

SKIP
No....Monopoly requires a certain level of mathematical skill that I don't think you've acquired. You know, adding and subtracting. The ability to understand numbers. It's hard.

ANDY
Jenga has that! You have to add and subtract blocks. (long beat) Okay, that was a stretch.


SKIP
Thank you for admitting it.

JACK
I like Jenga, Andy. It's a strong game. 

ANDY
Totes!

SKIP

What is this "totes" thing?

ANDY
It's short for totally, come on, get with the times.

WILL
He says it every chance he gets, drives me freaking crazy.

ANDY
That's just cuz you can't pull it off.


WILL
Neither can you!

SKIP
I hate that abbreviated shit. The big one at my school is "sogs." (pronounced s-oh-gz) 

JACK
What the hell does that mean?


SKIP
It's like "so good," except shorter.

ANDY
That's retarded!

WILL
They're all retarded! It's not like you don't have time to say the extra syllable.

ANDY

I don't. I have other things to do. 

WILL
You're an idiot.

JACK
Totes.

SKIP and WILL
OHHHHH!


SKIP
(to JACK) What does everybody say at your school?

JACK
What do you mean?

SKIP
Do you guys have like a sogs (s-og-gz) or a totes?


ANDY
Put those two together you get SCROTES!

WILL
Idiot.

JACK
I dunno, we didn't really have one.

WILL

Well good for you guys! I should have gone to school with you.

JACK
Nah, you wouldn't have liked it that much.

WILL
Why not?

JACK
I dunno.


WILL
What was wrong with it?

JACK
Nothing.

SKIP
Wow. You're being awfully descriptive.

JACK

 Well... okay. Fuck. I actually left before the semester ended.
 
SKIP
 (beat) What?
 
ANDY
 Woah, woah, woah. Hold the phone... what did you do?

 
JACK
 I left.
 
ANDY
 Just...left?
 
JACK

 Yeah.
 
SKIP
 Where did you go?
 
JACK
I took a road trip.


SKIP and ANDY
 GET OUT!
  
SKIP
 That's awesome!
 
WILL
Why didn't you tell us?


JACK
 I don't know. It wasn't a big deal.
 
ANDY
Are you shitting me?! That's huge!

SKIP
How long were you gone?


JACK
A little over a month... I got back like three weeks ago.

SKIP
Wow, that's awesome! I'm jealous.

WILL
 Wait...you've been home for three weeks? Why didn't you call us? (referencing ANDY too) We've been here.

 
JACK
 I know.
 
WILL
 I thought you were still at school. Did you not want us to know you were back?
 
JACK

 No, I wasn't trying to keep anything from you. I just needed some time alone.
 
ANDY
 Well, I don't care, I wanna know everything! Where'd you go? What'd you do? Who'd ya bang? Tell me everything!
 
JACK
 Everything?

 
ANDY
 Yeah.
 
JACK
 Okay...

THE OPEN ROAD


JACK
WELL I TOOK A MONTH OFF FROM SCHOOL
AND DECIDED TO GO ON A TRIP
 I PACKED MY BAGS AND KISSED MY MOM GOODBYE
 
ANDY
 You kissed your Mom Dude? Gross...

 
JACK
AND I GOT INTO MY CAR
WHAT A LOUSY PIECE OF SHIT
BUT I DIDN'T CARE
I JUST NEEDED TO TRY
AND GO DRIVING DOWN THE COAST
IN THE NICE DAYS OR THE RAIN
I WORE THE SAME CLOTHES AND GOT FOOD ON THE GO


SKIP
Wendy's?

JACK
I TORE AROUND THOSE CURVES
JUST SPEEDING THROUGH THE PLAINS
SOMETIMES I WENT SO FAST I WANTED TO EXPLODE
CAUSE IT WAS JUST ME
 AND THE OPEN ROAD

 
I STOPPED AT ALL THE PARKS
AND SLEPT UNDER THE SKY
AND WHEN I WOKE I DROVE THE REST OF THE DAY
I TOOK SHORTCUTS THROUGH PEOPLES' YARDS
AND RAN MY GAS TANK CLOSE TO DRY
AND WHEN I SPED BY COPS I KNEW JUST WHAT TO SAY
AFTER THE FOURTEENTH TIME
WHEN I WAS DRIVING THROUGH THE EAST

WITH THE WINDOWS ROLLED DOWN LOW
THERE WAS SO MUCH AIR THAT I COULD HARDLY BREATHE
I TAUGHT MYSELF THE LAND FROM THE BLUE RIDGE TO POCONOS
I BECAME AN EXPERT ON HOW TRAFFIC FLOWED
I LOVED MY LIFE ALONE
 ON THE OPEN ROAD
 
AND THEN I MET THIS BOY AT A TRUCK STOP IN DES MOINES

HE WOULDN'T HITCH CAUSE HE HAD TOO MUCH PRIDE
SO I OFFERED HIM A RIDE

AND WE LEARNED ABOUT EACH OTHERS LIVES
AS WE TALKED ALL THROUGH THE NIGHT
AND WHEN HE THOUGHT THE TIME WAS RIGHT
HE KISSED ME IN THE CAR BENEATH A STARLESS SKY
AND WITH THAT KISS HE OPENED UP MY MIND
AND WE WENT DRIVING

WE WERE DRIVING
WE WERE DRIVING
JUST ME
A BEAUTIFUL BOY
 AND THE OPEN ROAD
 
(Silence)
 

SKIP
Wow. (beat) Have you told your mom yet?

JACK
Yup.

SKIP
 What'd she say?

 
JACK
She said she always knew -

SKIP
 So did I.
 
JACK
  - which was annoying.

 
SKIP
 Oh. Sorry.
 
JACK
 That's okay.
 
SKIP

 (pause) Well... that's huge man, I'm really prouda you!
 
JACK
Thanks.

(SKIP stares at WILL)

WILL

 What? Oh. Yeah. No, I know. That's awesome! I'm sorry... it's just... new.
 
JACK
For me too.

WILL
It's great though!

ANDY

Yeah -

JACK
 Thanks.

(silence)

SKIP
Well I don't know about you fellas, but I think this calls for a celebration! Everybody ready to get drunk?


ANDY
Fuck yeah!

JACK
Absolutely.

SKIP
Great! Who's coming with me to the car?

WILL

You already got it?

SKIP
Of course. Always a step ahead, amigo!

JACK
I'll help.

SKIP
Sweet. (to WILL and ANDY) Be right back. 


(SKIP and JACK start to exit.)

(to Jack) Did you touch my butt?

JACK
 Shut up!
 
WILL

 (to ANDY) Well... I wasn't expecting that.

(Silence. ANDY is sitting on the player's bench staring at his phone)

Andy?

ANDY
Yeah?


WILL
What is it?

ANDY
Nothing.

WILL
What's wrong?

ANDY

(biting) Nothing. I'm fine.

WILL
You don't look fine.

ANDY
(beat) Are you?


WILL
Yeah.

ANDY
Good.

WILL
Okay, what is that supposed to mean?

ANDY

Jesus, Will what do you want me to say?

WILL
 I dunno. Why is this bothering you so much?
 
THINGS ARE DIFFERENT
 
ANDY
DON'T LOOK AT ME THAT WAY

I'M NOT CRAZY
I DON'T NEED TO KNOW
HOW YOU'D LIKE ME TO FEEL
NOW IF IT DOESN'T BOTHER YOU
THAT HE'S CHANGING, FINE
BUT DON'T PRETEND THAT THIS
IS NOT A BIGGER DEAL
JACK IS GONE TO ME
I JUST WATCHED HIM DISAPPEAR

IT MAY BE WRONG TO LEAVE 
BUT I DON'T WANT HIM HERE.

WILL
 Don't...
 
ANDY
WELL WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
 

WILL
JUST DON'T GO
I KNOW IT'S NEW 
BUT WHY SHOULD YOU HAVE TO LEAVE JUST CUZ HE'S OPENED UP
HE'S OUR BEST FRIEND, DON'T WE ASK THAT OF HIM?
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME, IT'LL JUST TAKE SOME MORE
TO WORK IN OUR OLD WAY
OKAY?


ANDY
NO
I WON'T SAY I DON'T CARE
I LOOK AND MY FRIEND ISNT THERE
I DON'T LIKE BEING LIED TO

WILL
 OH, AND I DO?


ANDY
WHEN THINGS GO WRONG
YOU ALWAYS SEE THE UPSIDE
 WHY?
 
WILL
CAUSE I CAN STILL SEE HIM WHEN I LOOK AT HIS FACE
HE'S NOT ANY DIFFERENT, HE'S JUST IN A DIFFERENT PLACE

SO THINK ABOUT WHAT YOU SAY
CAUSE PEOPLE ARE ALLOWED TO CHANGE
 WHY GREET THAT CHANGE BY CAUSING HIM PAIN?
 
ANDY
 I DON'T WANT TO HURT HIM
 
WILL

CAN'T YOU SEE THAT YOU WILL?

ANDY
LOOK, THIS ISNT MY BURDEN

WILL
YOU'RE HIS FRIEND
 

  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
  
  
  WILL
YOU SHOULD TRY UNTIL YOU
UNDERSTAND HIM

ANDY
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
UNDERSTAND ME


WILL
THIS ISNT WRONG, ANDY THIS IS JUST NEW
YOU CANT WRITE OFF JACK CAUSE HE'S DIFFERENT THAN YOU

  
  
   
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   	
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   	
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
  

WILL
YOU'RE NOT
WRONG, BUT... 
NEITHER IS THIS ANDY, THIS IS JUST NEW
HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT YOU CANT LOVE HIM
JACK NEVER SAID THAT YOU HAD TO LIVE
YOUR LIFE ONE WAY
LET GO OF YOUR BIAS, HE IS YOUR FRIEND
OR THIS COULD BE


  ANDY
DONT MAKE IT SOUND 
LIKE I'M WRONG
 
I WISH THINGS COULD STAY 
THE WAY THEY WERE ALL
ALONG, BUT...
THINGS ARE DIFFERENT, WILL
THINGS HAVE CHANGED
JACK IS NO LONGER WITH US
ONLY THE SURFACE REMAINS
NOW ITS JUST YOU AND ME 
AND SKIP. WE'LL WORK AS THREE

  
  
WILL and ANDY

NOT FOUR ANYMORE

WILL
Andy -

ANDY
WHAT ARE YOU ASKING ME TO DO?

WILL
LET IT GO


ANDY
IS THIS FOR HIM OR FOR YOU?

WILL
JUST LET IT GO

ANDY
WHY ARE YOU PUTTING THIS ON ME 

WILL

LOOK, IM NOT SAYING I DISAGREE
BUT PLEASE, FOR ME, KEEP QUIET

ANDY
Fine.

WILL
Fine.

(ANDY sits on the bleachers, while WILL walks down the field. JACK and SKIP enter carrying two cases of Natty Light)


SKIP
The pride parade is back!

(JACK and SKIP set the cases on the player's bench.)

WILL
What did you get?

SKIP
Only the best for my boys! Natty Light!


(SKIP tosses a can of Natty Light to WILL)

WILL
(sarcastic) Mmm... Did you steal those from your Dad's fridge?

SKIP
Nope! (proudly) Bought em.


WILL
How?

SKIP
 THIS guy!

(SKIP flashes a fake ID)

WILL

Let me see that.

(SKIP hands the ID to WILL)

SKIP
(recites the info from memory) Julio Mendez. 5225 Ridgemont Court. Ironwood, Minnesota. September 7th, 1983.

JACK
Impressive.


SKIP
I know.

WILL
This looks nothing like you.

SKIP
Sure it does!

WILL

This kid is Hispanic. 

SKIP
Well it worked didn't it?

(SKIP takes his ID away from WILL)

JACK
 (grabbing a beer) You know, I didn't have a single drop of alcohol this past year, and guess what, I'm still sane.

 
SKIP
Yeah but you're gay. See what sobriety can do to you?

WILL
(WILL, covering, takes a sip.) This stuff is terrible!

SKIP
Then don't drink it.


WILL
Just saying, I thought you had better taste then this.

SKIP
Listen, I had ten dollars.  For ten dollars, this is quality.

JACK
(to WILL) Did what's her face call?


WILL
Nope.

SKIP
How long are we gonna to wait around for this girl?

WILL
I don't know. You got places to be?

SKIP

No, I just don't wanna be out here all night! That's all!

ANDY
Amen to that.

WILL
(to JACK, about SKIP) So... what do you think of this new look?

JACK

I wasn't gonna say anything but, you kinda look like a pothead.

WILL
I think he looks like Anne Heche.

SKIP
I don't really care if it looks good or not.

WILL
You should.


SKIP
Why? Who am I trying to impress?

ANDY
Not us, apparently.

JACK
I have to admit, I'm a little surprised. I thought you were gonna come back looking like a total Ivy Leauge prep. You know, pink polo with the popped collar...

SKIP

Never! My roommate was like that. He wore plaid shorts every day of the week. It'd be 15 degrees outside and he'd still be wearing plaid shorts and boat shoes. Dumbass.

WILL
Sounds like your kind of guy.

SKIP
Not to mention the fact that his dad bought him a Lexus when he graduated from high school. 

WILL
Jesus.


JACK
I got a check from my grandma that bounced.

SKIP
Yeah. And he was all pissed off cause it wasn't a Beamer.

ANDY
Shut up!

WILL

So what did you say?

SKIP
About what?

WILL
To him - about the car.

SKIP
Nothing.


WILL
Why not?

SKIP
What was I supposed to say?

WILL
I dunno, a guy like that - I figured you'd let him have it.

SKIP

Why would I "let him have it?" Nothing I'm gonna say is gonna change anything, so why waste the energy?

JACK
...When you can just grow your hair out.

SKIP
Exactly!

WILL
Are you kidding me?!


SKIP
What?

WILL
 I've just never heard of you backing down from an opportunity like that. You're the most opinionated guy I know.
    
SKIP
My opinion doesn't mean shit Will! It's just one opinion. So why not go with the flow? I mean I'm doing your prank, aren't I?


WILL
It's not my prank! It's OUR prank!

SKIP
Right. I forgot. Sorry. Who cares anyway.

WILL
I care!

SKIP

Sure, but no matter how much you CARE, it doesn't matter. No one really listens to anyone anyway, we're all too wrapped up in ourselves. So why should I be any different?

WILL
Because you are. You always have been. It's why we're friends.

SKIP
I thought we were friends because we sucked at football.

WILL
No, come on. We're friends because we're -


SKIP
 Different? No we're not. You'd like to think we are. But you're sitting here, talking about how things should change and not doing shit. Just like everybody else.

GENERATION APATHY

   SKIP
IN A WORLD THAT DEFINES ITSELF WITH X's Y2K's and Z's
YOU'RE PRESENT FOR A 3RD WORLD WAR

THATS REAL BUT YOU CHOOSE NOT TO SEE
YOU DON'T CARE OR EVER DARE OUTSIDE OF YOUR COMPLACENCY
BUT IT'S NOT JUST YOU, THERE'S A NEW WORLD ORDER:
GENERATION APATHY 

WILL
I am not like that.

SKIP
Yes you are, you just don't want to hear it.


SKIP
WE'RE ALL VIRGINS WHO ARE BURGEONING WITH READINESS FOR MORE
BUT WE'VE GOT PORNOS IN OUR DRAWER
SO WE DON'T HAVE TO USE THE DOOR 
WE FEED A NEED TO NEVER BLEED UNLESS WE'RE ABSOLUTELY SURE 
 WE GO THROUGH PAINSTAKING MEANS TO NEVER FEEL PAIN ANYMORE

WE USED TO BE YOUNG AND STUPID BUT NOW WE'RE JUST YOUNG 

CAUSE WE DON'T ADMIT THE STUPID SHIT WE'VE DONE NOW THAT REAL LIFE HAS BEGUN
OUR GENERATION'S WAY OVERSEXED AND UNDERLOVED 
AND UNDERWHELMED BY ALL OF THE ABOVE

WILL
Skip, I think that's a -

SKIP
 Am I wrong?


WE COMPLAIN ABOUT OUR PERFECT LIVES WITH BIGGER WORDS THAN MOST
WE SPEW OUT FACTS AND FIND IT RELAXING TO TALK SHIT AS WE BOAST 
ABOUT ME AND ME AND ME AND ME, LET'S ALL RAISE A TOAST 
TO THE GENERATION THAT'LL TURN THIS NATION 
FROM A SUPERPOWER INTO A GHOST 

OUR FATHERS ARE COMMUTERS, BUT WE'RE STUCK IN OUR COMPUTERS 
WHICH TAKE US ALL AWAY FROM ONE ANOTHER, BUT WHO CARES
CUZ WE'RE TOO OCCUPIED TO NOTICE WHAT WAS THERE HAS DIED 

BETWEEN THE FAMILIES WHO USED TO LOVE EACH OTHER, CUZ WHO CARES
THE PROBLEMS OF THE WORLD WE'RE IN WILL ALWAYS BE RIGHT HERE
BUT RATHER THAN FIXING THEM WE'LL JUST JOIN IN WITH THE CHEER
WHO CARES
WHO CARES
WHO CARES WHO CARES WHO CARES
WHO CARES?
WE MAY GRADUATE WITH HONORS BUT THERE'S NO HONOR IN IT
WE ARE RUNNING A RACE BUT WE'RE OKAY IF WE DON'T WIN IT 

WE ARE SMART BUT WE DON'T TRY - THE "DO I HAVE TO?" KIND OF GUY
WHO'LL NEVER RISK AND NEVER FAIL IF HE CAN SPIN IT 
CHIVALRY AND BRAVERY AND THE QUALITIES WE USED TO BE 
ARE NOW ONLY A MEMORY 
AND WHAT I'M STILL WONDERING 
IS WHAT'S THE MOST EXPENSIVE THING I CAN GET FOR FREE 

I FEEL BAD BUT CAN'T HELP THE LAUGHTER 
AT THE GENERATION THAT COMES AFTER 

 GENERATION APATHY

 (WILL pulls his phone out of his pocket and walks away)

SKIP
(to WILL) Where are you going?

WILL

(agitated) Calling Hannah.

SKIP
Are you mad at me?

WILL
 No, I just wanna know where she is.

(WILL walks down the field, away from the guys and starts to call Patricia.)


SKIP
(to JACK and ANDY) You see, no one wants to hear it.

(WILL closes his phone and puts it back in his pocket)

AFTER ALL

WILL
WHEN I FEEL ALONE, I HAVE THESE FRIENDS OF MINE

THE OTHER HALVES OF ME, WHO KEEP ME SANE IN TROUBLED TIMES
AND WHEN I LOSE MY WAY, I HAVE THEM THERE IN THE BACK OF MY MIND
 AND THEN I DON'T FEEL LONELY AFTER ALL

(JACK notices WILL's notebook under the bench)
 
JACK
What's that?


SKIP
 What?

(JACK picks up the notebook.)

JACK
(reads) "The Personal Memoirs of William Frances Levinson."

SKIP

What!? Let me see. 

ANDY
What are you doing?

SKIP
(flipping through the pages of the notebook) Exploring. 

JACK

Maybe we shouldn't read it.

SKIP
Or maybe we should. "They're was no real reason why we should have been friend." ...Is this about us?



  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   	
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
   
  
  



WILL
WHEN I FEEL ALONE
I HAVE THESE FRIENDS OF MINE
THE OTHER HALVES OF ME
WHO KEEP ME SANE IN TROUBLED TIMES
AND WHEN I LOSE MY WAY, I HAVE THEM	
THERE IN THE BACK OF MY MIND
AND THEN I DON'T FEEL LONELY

JACK
" - Jack was incredibly small for his age. He was targeted by the same
 group of 12th graders who decided that he would fit nicely in a trashcan-"
  
SKIP
"Skip was a military brat whose father insisted that his boy maintain a GI Joe
 style crew cut. On his way to school every day, Skip looked like a toy soldier storming the campus-"
   

ANDY
 Let me see that! "Andy's brothers all played Varsity for the Beavers,
 so it was very important that he not only make the team as a freshman, but that he also make All-State."  



WILL
BUT WHEN I LOSE MY WAY
THEY DON'T SEEM TO CARE
THAT WHEN I LOSE MY WAY
THEY ARE NEVER THERE
AND WHEN I LOSE MY WAY

WHERE ARE THEY WHEN I GET LONELY
WELL NOBODY ASKED ME IF WE'RE ALLOWED TO CHANGE
MAYBE I'M THE ONLY ONE WHO STAYED THE SAME
 
AND NOW I AM STILL ALONE WITH ALL THESE FRIENDS OF MINE
THE OTHER HALVES OF ME WHO RAN AWAY IN TROUBLED TIMES
AND NOW I FEEL THE SHAME OF HOLDING ONTO WHAT'S NO LONGER MINE
MAYBE THINGS ARE DIFFERENT AFTER ALL
AND I JUST NEVER SAW IT AT ALL


ANDY
"Andy seemed destined for gridiron glory, except for one minor problem: he was a terrible athlete. On the first day of tryouts Andy managed to run the ball into the wrong end zone. Twice."

(Everyone except ANDY laughs at this)

Whatever man! At least I touched the ball. You guys didn't even make it past wind sprints. 

JACK
(sarcastic) Yeah, you're amazing.

 
(WILL runs over)
 
WILL
What are you doing? Don't!

ANDY
What?

WILL

Please don't read that.

ANDY
Why?

WILL
Cause it's not yours.

SKIP
What is it, a diary?


WILL
It's nothing. Give it back.

ANDY
Come on, we're just getting to the good part!

WILL
Look, could you not. It's private- 

SKIP

Private? Like...a diary?

WILL
It's not a diary!

ANDY
Quiet I'm reading! "The seniors called him Conan, but I don't think Andy ever really understood why." (to WILL) What!? Yeah I did! Cause I was fucking ripped!

SKIP

And now look at you.

ANDY
(doesn't understand) What? I look good!

WILL
Andy, please -

ANDY

 I've only got a paragraph left, lemme finish. "When we left the field that day becoming friends seemed like a last resort. But it actually resulted in an unexpected brotherhood. We knew we were different and as we spent more and more time together, we began to loath the idea of being 'normal.' We'd never be homecoming kings or football stars but in the grand scheme, that didn't matter. Our friendship was defined by who we were, by our standards. Life pushes you in a direction whether you choose it or not. Oddly enough, life turned us around so we could find each other."

(Silence)

JACK
It's really good Will.

WILL
 Thanks.


 (ANDY slams the notebook shut and tosses it to Jack)

ANDY
Well I hate it! 

SKIP
Come on Andy! We never would have become friends if you'd run those touchdowns into the right end zone. (beat) Either time.


(The guys laugh)

ANDY
True, but it's a story, can't you change it a little? Artistic likeness?

SKIP
License?

ANDY
That's what I said! 


JACK
(flipping through the pages) There's a lot here.

WILL
(embarrassed) I know.

SKIP

When did you write all this?

WILL
At school.

ANDY
Is that why you were in the room so much? I always thought you were, you know...

WILL
Well...that too.


JACK
 Hey asshole, what does this mean? (reading) "When I first met Jack, he was wearing baggy sweatpants and a jersey that was almost twice his size. All I could think was that Jack bore a striking resemblance to Popeye." I don't get it!? Why Popeye?
 
WILL
Cuz you were so small.

JACK

So?

WILL
When you put pads on you looked like you'd eaten your spinach.

(SKIP laughs at him)

SKIP
That's so true. Well put.

JACK

Oh shut up! GI Joe.

SKIP
You shut up, Popeye is so much worse.

ANDY
Besides, where's all the shit about you?

WILL
What are you talking about?


ANDY
Why isn't there anything in there about you being a fatty?

WILL
I was not!

ANDY
 No no no, don't lie. You were a fucking tub! You were so fat your belly came out from under your jersey.


(SKIP laughs hard)
 
WILL
Whatever man, that was baby fat!

ANDY
 Dude that was not baby fat. That was fat fat. You came to school with like twenty Snack Packs a day. You looked like Chunk from The Goonies!


(They all laugh)

WILL
You guys suck!


SKIP
Truffle Shuffle, truffle shuffle...

JACK and ANDY

 Truffle shuffle, truffle shuffle...

THE GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS

ANDY
CHUNK!

SKIP
POPEYE THE SAILOR MAN


WILL
GI JOE

WILL and ANDY
THE AMERICAN HERO

JACK
AND CONAN
THE BARBARIAN
NOT O'BRIEN


WILL
LOOK
WE ARE STILL THE BOYS
FRESHMAN YEAR, WE WERE QUEER
SORRY
WE WERE "DIFFERENT"
 THAT WASN'T A GAY JOKE
 

JACK
YOU WEIGH THE SAME THAT YOU DID BACK THEN
BUT YOU WERE FIVE FOOT FOUR, NOW YOU'RE FIVE FOOT TEN
WELL AT LEAST FIVE NINE, WELL AT LEAST YOU'RE TALLER

SKIP
LOOK WHO'S TALKING ABOUT BEING AN AWKWARD MESS
YOU WERE SO GANGLY, YOUR ARMS JUST DANGLED
THEY WRAPPED 'ROUND TWICE WHEN YOU'D FOLD 'EM 'CROSS YOUR CHEST


ANDY
AND I WAS STRONG

JACK
BUT YOU WERE DUMB

SKIP
STILL ARE

ANDY

SHUT UP

WILL
YOU ARE

WILL and ANDY
YOUR MOM!!

ALL (except ANDY)

SEE

ALL
MAN THIS BRINGS ME
BACK TO THOSE GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS

WILL
WHEN WE WOULD RUN FROM BULLIES

JACK

WHEN WE WOULD HIDE IN TRASH CANS

SKIP
WHEN ALL THEY WANTED TO DO
WAS PUT US IN ONE

ANDY
AND WE'D SAY WE HAD GIRLFRIENDS

WILL

BUT NOBODY COULD MEET THEM

JACK
CAUSE THEY WERE ONLINE

SKIP
AND PROBABLY MEN

ALL
MAN THIS BRINGS ME

BACK TO THINGS I
HAVENT THOUGHT ABOUT SINCE THOSE GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS

WILL
HEY
WHAT ABOUT YOU
MR. YOU-KNOW-WHO
JUNIOR ROTC

SKIP

YEA THAT WAS ME
IT WAS MY DAD'S PLAN, BUT I GOT SOMETHING OUT OF IT
I COULD END YOUR LIFE WITH MY BARE HANDS

WILL
FUCK YOU, BRING IT ON

ANDY
WATCH OUT, ARE YOU NUTS?


JACK
DON'T FIGHT... COME ON GUYS

SKIP
YOU ARE MINE!

ALL
SEE, THIS IS WHAT THE GOOD OLD DAYS SHOULD BE LIKE

JACK

FOOTBALL IN THE LIGHTS

WILL
PIZZA EVERY NIGHT

ANDY
HORSEFACE EVERY NIGHT

SKIP
STREET FIGHTER 2


ALL
ARE THE THINGS THAT REMIND ME OF YOU AND ME AND HERE

DREAMING OF AMAZING THINGS
THE NEW IDEAS THAT WE WOULD BRING
TO A WORLD THAT ISN'T GROWING
ISNT GOING WHERE IT COULD BE
LIFE ISNT ABOUT WHAT IS 
BUT WHAT SHOULD BE

GENERATION YOU 
AND ME AND HERE

WILL
GOOD OLD GLORY DAYS ALWAYS SEEM TO SAY GOODBYE

SKIP
AND THEY BECOME THE PAST TENSE THAT WE APPLY TO OUR LIVES

ANDY

THE GOOD OLD DAYS ARE ONLY GOOD WHILE YOU'RE THERE

JACK
AND WHEN THEY'RE DONE, THEY'RE NOT AS FUN
EVEN THOUGH YOU STILL DO CARE
 MAN I MISS THOSE...

SKIP
UGLY GYM CLOTHES


ANDY
WILL'S BIG JEW NOSE

WILL
ANDY'S SISTER'S PANTYHOSE

ANDY
Hey!

JACK

MAN I MISS THOSE

SKIP
HIGH SCHOOL DANCE WOES

ANDY
BATHROOM PEEP SHOWS

WILL
WATCHING US GROW


ALL
MAN I MISS THOSE
GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE
MAN I MISS THOSE
GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS

WILL
This is so perfect.


JACK
What?

WILL
This. The four us back together again. I missed this so much.

ANDY
Fuck you!

WILL

No, shut up, I didn't mean it like that! I just - I feel like I missed out on everything that happened with you guys this year. Makes me feel like a bad friend.

SKIP
That's because you're really bad at keeping in touch.

WILL
You're one to talk.

SKIP
Touche. But whatever man, we had to separate at some point - we weren't going to live in the same neighborhood forever. 


WILL
I know, I know.

SKIP
It's just reality.

JACK
To be honest, if I'd been around you guys all year I never would have gone and done what I did. And I needed to. I needed that time away from you fools.

SKIP

I don't know if you needed it. I could have told you -

JACK
Shut up jerk. 

WILL
I hated this year.

SKIP
Why?


WILL
It just wasn't for me. Everyone kept walking around being like "oh I love this, we're free" and I just never got that. 

SKIP
No I hear you. That's pretty much how I felt too.

ANDY
I don't understand you guys. I loved college.

JACK

I don't remember getting any glowing emails from you.

ANDY
I couldn't write em, I dropped my laptop in the sink.

SKIP
That's the lamest excuse ever.

WILL
No he's serious.


JACK
Why was your laptop anywhere near a sink?

ANDY
I don't have an Ipod, so I took my computer to the bathroom to listen to some music while I shaved.

SKIP
Wow, that's brilliant. You never got a new one?

ANDY

Nope.

JACK
How'd you do your homework?

ANDY
I didn't.

WILL
See why I didn't have anything to write home about?


JACK
I just feel like this is how things were supposed to go. We needed this time apart.

SKIP
I agree.

WILL
 You're prolly right.


(WILL's phone rings, Brittany Spears "Toxic")

SKIP
Is that really your ring?

WILL
What?

SKIP
Yikes man. 


WILL
Leave her alone. (answers the phone) Hello!? Horsef---Hannah? Hey! Hi. So did you find the... Really? (disappointed) Oh.    

ANDY
What? 


WILL
(into the phone) No, it's okay. Don't worry about it. 

ANDY
What is she saying?

WILL
We'll just figure something else out. 


ANDY
Let me talk to her!

WILL
(to ANDY) Stop! (into the phone) It's gonna be fine. Thanks though.

ANDY

Give me the phone!

WILL
Get off ... (they struggle for the phone) Andy!

ANDY
(takes the phone from WILL) Well well well. Hannah Hannah Hannah. What a coincidence.


WILL
Come on dude!!

ANDY
(to WILL) I got this! (into the phone) No this isn't Will anymore, it's his best friend Mr. Andrew Scott. Hello. Do you remember me? Oh Hannah Hannah Hannah. We went to school together! I was that well-sculpted fellow that sat behind you during Conceptual Physics. I got a C because of you. Anyway, listen we really need this key from you because this is sort of a big deal and we're in a bit of time crunch. So is there anything you could ... (waits for a moment) Oh. Ohhhh. Ummm... Friday? I... ummm... I can't do Friday. Cuz...I got...into a car accident. I know, it was awful, thirteen car pile-up. Thankfully no one died. Oh yea I'm fine, I just...broke a few bones. 


SKIP
What are you doing??? (all the guys are in hysterics)

ANDY
Yeah, sure, maybe we can hang out once I'm feeling up to it. Shouldn't be more than a couple of...months - anyway thanks for all your support. Talk to you later. Ok. All right. Bye now. (hangs up) Jesus!

SKIP

What the hell was that?

ANDY
That girl is intense!

WILL
Told you.

ANDY
(in post-traumatic stress) I'm never making fun of her again.


JACK
Um...so what's going on with the key!?

WILL
Oh. Apparently it's in the building.  

JACK
What!?

ANDY

She says it could be in the maintenance closet. 

JACK
So what did she give us?

WILL
Who knows.

ANDY
(sarcastic) We probably have her Dad's car keys. 


JACK
What are we supposed to do now?

SKIP
(beat) You know... we could always try and sneak into the building?

ANDY
Keep talking!


WILL
How?

SKIP
Well... there's that window in the gym. The one we used to sneak out of during assemblies.

ANDY
Oh my God, why didn't I think of that!

SKIP

 We could definitely get in through there. And if the closet's locked, screw it, let's just break in.

ARE YOU READY REPRISE

SKIP
AREN'T YOU READY FOR TONIGHT?

WILL
I'VE BEEN READY SINCE 5 YEARS AGO


JACK
TRESPASSING'S A CRIME, YOU KNOW

SKIP
THEN WE'LL ABORT IF COPS SHOW

ANDY
I like where your head's at.


WILL
I DUNNO...

SKIP
ARE YOU SCARED NOW?

WILL
NO

ANDY

I'LL GO WITH YOU

SKIP
 (to JACK and WILL) IF YOU SEE SOMEONE FIND SOMETHIN LOUD TO DO

SKIP and THE GUYS
NOW ARE YOU READY FOR READY FOR TONIGHT...

ANDY

 All right. Let's do this!

(SKIP and ANDY exit, whooping and hollering.)

WILL
SSShhhhhhhhhhhhh! Guys!

JACK
They're going to set off some alarm in that building and we're all gonna get caught.


WILL
No they wont! Jack, bad vibes!

JACK
Okay fine. Good vibes, good vibes. But you know I'm right.

WILL
Probably.

(Long silence) 


So... is there a guy? Like a guy, like a boyfriend guy? Is that what you call it?

JACK
Sure. You can call it that.

WILL
Sorry. (beat) So is there?


JACK
No. There isn't.

WILL
What about the guy you met. You know, the one that you... (makes weird gestures with his hands)

JACK
I know who you're talking about.

WILL

Okay. Yeah. What about him? 

JACK
I dunno. He lives in Iowa. I live here. It's not like I'm gonna start doing long distance. (beat) We're friends on Myspace, that's something, right?

WILL
(laughs) I guess. (beat) So, can I ask, how long you've known? I mean, was it something that you've always known or just suddenly realized or... what?


JACK
(wryly) Why so curious?

WILL
I dunno - I mean, I just wanna understand what you're going through.

JACK
Well... I think I always kinda knew on some level. I just fought it and then I realized I didn't have to. I can actually be who I am and if people don't like who I am then fuck them. I'm fine.


(WILL nods, beat)

Does that bother you?

WILL
No, of course not. 

JACK
Good. (beat) What do you think Andy thinks?


WILL
(caught off guard) I don't know... I'm not...

JACK
I'm just curious. I didn't know if he said anything to you -

WILL
What would he have said?


JACK
I don't know. But he hasn't really said much of anything since - I just don't think he's too thrilled.

WILL
Andy's weird. "What do you think Andy thinks?" is kind of a loaded question?

JACK
Yea. But I can tell when something's bothering him.

WILL

(beat) Well ...okay. Okay, he did say something.

JACK
He did? What's he say? 

WILL
He just said he's not really all that cool with it, and you should have told us a while ago. Like you've been lying to us or blah blah blah. I dunno, it was pretty much bullshit.

JACK

He said that?

WILL
...Yeah.

JACK
Why didn't you tell me?

WILL
Cuz he asked me not to. He didn't want to ruin the night. But I'd feel like a bad friend not telling you.


JACK
Should I talk to him?

WILL
NO! I mean it'd be better if you didn't, cause I told him I wouldn't tell you. So... I'm sorry... should I not have?

JACK
No you did the right thing. I just don't understand why he'd think that? Why would I try to screw things up? 

WILL

It's not you, Jack. It's him.

THE THING ABOUT ANDY

WILL
HE'S NEVER BEEN LIKE US
THAT'S BEEN CLEAR SINCE BACK THEN
SO THE FACT THAT HE'D CHANGE WITHOUT TELLING US WHEN IS NOT TOO SURPRISING
CAUSE IT'S ALWAYS BEEN CLEAR
THAT THERE'S SOMETHING GOING ON HERE


WITH ANDY 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY
IS HOW CLOSE WE ARE TO HIM
AND HOW MUCH WE STILL DON'T KNOW
ANDY
THE THING ABOUT ANDY
IS WHAT HE IS HOLDING BACK
THAT HE THINKS HE CAN'T LET GO

SO HE MAY NEVER SHOW
THE THING ABOUT -

JACK
MAYBE
THE THING ABOUT ANDY
IS HE DOESN'T KNOW HIMSELF
THE WAY THAT HIS BEST FRIENDS DO
MAYBE

THE TRUTH IS THAT ANDY
JUST ISNT AS SMART AS US
 SO HOW CAN WE EXPECT HIM TO?
 
WILL
OR MAYBE THAT'S NOT TRUE
AND WE DON'T KNOW ANDY

JACK

BUT HOW CAN THAT BE?
HE'S STILL THE PERSON WHO
WE STOOD NEXT TO SINCE WE WERE KIDS

WILL
BUT OBVIOUSLY
THE BEST FRIEND YOU THOUGHT YOU KNEW
WOULD NEVER DO WHAT HE JUST DID

JACK and WILL

IT'S EMBARRASING THAT WE 
CAN LOOK SO HARD AND STILL NOT SEE

JACK
WHAT SOMEONE ELSE COULD FEEL FOR YOU...

WILL
WHEN YOU DON'T MAKE A MOVE...

JACK

WHAT FAKE FRIENDS SAY AND REAL FRIENDS DO...

WILL
IT'S JUST ANOTHER WAY TO PROVE...

JACK and WILL
THAT I NEVER REALLY KNEW
A THING ABOUT
		
WILL

ANDY
THE THING ABOUT ANDY
IS HOW MUCH HE DOESN'T GET
 THE WORK THAT A BEST FRIEND DOES
 
JACK
ANDY
THE THING ABOUT ANDY

IS HE'S BETTER FRIENDS WITH US
 THAN WE ARE TO HIM BECAUSE
 
WILL and JACK
THERE NEVER REALLY WAS
 A THING ABOUT -

 (JACK leans in and kisses WILL on the cheek. WILL pulls away.  Silence.)


WILL
 What was that for?

(Silence. JACK leans in and kisses WILL on the lips. ANDY and SKIP appear, having seen the second kiss.)


ANDY
 What are you doing?


(JACK and WILL pull away from each other)

JACK
Shit.

ANDY
Will, what are you DOING?!

WILL
Andy - It was nothing.


ANDY
Nothing? That was nothing?

SKIP
What's going on?

JACK
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have -

ANDY

I don't believe this.

(ANDY grabs his jacket off the bleachers)

WILL
Andy, come on, we need to talk about this...

ANDY
Will. Do. You. Realize what you just did?!


WILL
You're right! I'm sorry. But it's not what you -

ANDY
Fuck this.

(ANDY turns to exit)

WILL
Andy, come on -


JACK (overlapping WILL)
Andy, please, can we talk for a second?

ANDY
About what?

JACK
Well you're obviously upset.


ANDY
(to Jack) You came here tonight and dropped this shit on us and thought that everything would be fine. It's NOT fine. You lied to us -

JACK
What?

SKIP

 Jesus, he didn't lie to you!

WILL
Guys, please -

JACK (overlapping WILL)
No, you lied to me too, Andy. Will told me what you said.


WILL
Jack - 

ANDY
What?

JACK
That you couldn't deal with it. That you've been sitting here all night not saying anything. Why not, why don't you just talk to me?

ANDY

(to WILL) Why would you tell him that....

JACK
He was being a good friend, Andy. I think I have the right to know.

ANDY
(to WILL) I don't believe you. 


SKIP
Why is this bothering you so much?

JACK 
I didn't tell you earlier, because I wasn't ready yet, Andy-

ANDY
Look, do whatever you want. I'm going.

(ANDY starts to exit)


SKIP
Why? What the fuck is your deal right now?

WILL
 Everybody STOP IT! (to ANDY) You're right! I'm sorry. Look its over. (ANDY starts to leave again. Will grabs him) Andy, LISTEN TO ME!


FORGET ABOUT IT

WILL
WHEN YOU WERE YOUNG
DIDN'T YOU HAVE DREAMS THAT YOU LET GO OF
CAUSE SOMEBODY TOLD YOU 
THAT YOU WEREN'T ALLOWED TO DREAM THE WAY YOU DO
DIDN'T YOU?


ANDY
I USED TO.

(ANDY turns to exit)

WILL
HEY!
WE'RE STILL HERE
UNDER THESE ELECTRIC STARS
AND ITS CLEAR THIS IS NOT HOW WE USUALLY ARE

BUT NOW WE'RE GONNA RELEARN HOW TO FIT 
SO NO MATTER WHAT YOU'RE THINKING OVER THERE
PLEASE JUST
FORGET ABOUT IT

SKIP
HOW BOUT YOU STAY TO TELL US
WHY YOU'RE SO GOOD AT BEING SUCH A PRICK

JACK

Skip... 

SKIP
COME ON JACK, YOU KNOW IT'S TRUE 
WHAT DID WE DO?

JACK
NO, WHAT DID I DO 

ANDY

NOTHING, NOTHING YOU'RE PERFECT IT'S FINE
I'M THE ONE WHO'S OBVIOUSLY OUT OF LINE

SKIP
I AGREE BUT I DON'T THINK YOU DO

ANDY
WELL THAT'S PRETTY DAMN SMART OF YOU

SKIP

You know what, fuck you man -

JACK
STOP! THIS IS MY FAULT 
AND I'M SORRY
I NEVER SHOULD HAVE SAID OR DONE A THING

SKIP
What?!


JACK
IF I HAD KEPT MY MOUTH SHUT THIS EVENING
NO ONE WOULD BE OUT HERE ARGUING

SKIP
Come on -
DON'T APOLOGIZE TO HIM

ANDY
YEA DON'T APOLOGIZE TO ME 


WILL
THEN DON'T GO
PLEASE DON'T GO
NOTHING'S COLLAPSED
JUST A MOMENTARY LAPSE
STAY PLEASE
CAUSE YOU KNOW
WE CAN FIX THIS IF YOU DO


ANDY
YOU THINK I'D STAY FOR YOU? 

SKIP
LET HIM GO

WILL
NO LET THIS GO
(to SKIP) FORGET ABOUT IT

WHEN YOU SEE ALL THE INCONSISTENCIES
IN THE WAY WE SEE THE WORLD
(to ANDY) FORGET ABOUT IT
WHEN YOU LEARN SOMEONE YEARNS TO BE DIFFERENT
THINGS CAN CHANGE

ANDY
AS LONG AS WE DON'T FIGHT 


WILL
JUST FORGET ABOUT IT
AND MOVE ON
ALL RIGHT?

JACK
ALL RIGHT.

SKIP and ANDY
IT'S NOT THAT EASY!



  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
    
     
    
    
   
   
    
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
   
  

WILL
YES IT IS
 PEOPLE CHANGE
 AND PEOPLE LIE
 PEOPLE TRY TO SAVE A FRIENDSHIP
 IS IT SO HARD
 TO SEE WHY

  
SKIP and ANDY
IT'S NOT THAT EASY
JUST TO FORGET ABOUT THIS

JACK
THIS ISN'T US GUYS
WE'RE BETTER THAN THIS
SO LETS TRY

WILL
WE HAVE TO TRY
AND JUST FORGET ABOUT IT
COME ON GUYS

ANDY
DO YOU SEE WHAT YOU'RE DOING?





SKIP
HE DIDN'T DO ANYTHING TO YOU
  
JACK
I DON'T NEED YOU TO FIGHT MY BATTLES
  
SKIP
I'M TRYING TO PROTECT YOU
  
JACK
WELL DON'T, JUST...
  
  
  
  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
    
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
    
     
    
    
   
  
  WILL
   FORGET ABOUT IT
    FORGET ABOUT IT
    FORGET ABOUT IT
    FORGET ABOUT IT
    FORGET ABOUT IT
  
SKIP
WELL I'M SORRY BUT
I'M NOT GOING 
TO EVER...

JACK
FORGET ABOUT IT!
THIS ISN'T US GUYS
PLEASE JUST...

ANDY
SURE.
FINE.
DO YOU HEAR	YOURSELF!?


   
WILL, SKIP AND JACK
FORGET ABOUT IT

ANDY
YEA, YOU'RE RIGHT
BE YOURSELF  WILL
DON'T HOLD IT IN 
SAY YOU'RE A FAGGOT JUST LIKE HIM


(silence)

JACK
(disbelief) What did you just say?

ANDY
I didn't mean it like that... I just...

OTHER HUMAN BEINGS


JACK
(to ANDY)
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS
YOU NEVER DO TO OTHER HUMAN BEINGS
THAT NO ONE NEEDS TO LEARN
CUZ IT'S PART OF WHO WE ARE

BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND, DO YOU?
I MEAN, OTHER HUMAN BEINGS

CUZ IF YOU DID, YOU'D SEE
THAT YOU JUST WENT TOO FAR
CUZ WE HAVE THE ABILITY TO CHOOSE
WHAT WE MAKE A PERSON FEEL
SO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR WHO YOU LOSE
WHEN THE PAIN YOU INFLICT BECOMES REAL

		(ANDY starts to walk away)


SO BEFORE YOU GO, YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT OTHER HUMAN BEINGS
DO NOT ACCEPT 
WHEN YOU TALK LIKE THAT TO A FRIEND
SO, AS ONE OF THEM
WATCH WHAT YOU DO TO OTHER HUMAN BEINGS...

ANDY
(overlapping)

...LOOK WHO'S "SPEAKING OUT"
LIKE HE KNOWS ABOUT OTHER HUMAN BEINGS
JUST PUT THE BLAME ON ME
THEN DO WHATEVER YOU WANT

  
  
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    	
   
   
    
     
    
    	
   
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   	
   
    
     
    
    
     
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
   
   
    
     
    
    
   
   

JACK
YOU HAD THE ABILITY TO CHOOSE
WHAT YOU WERE GOING TO MAKE ME FEEL
SO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR WHO YOU LOSE
WHEN THE PAIN YOU INFLICT BECOMES REAL
SO BEFORE I GO, YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT OTHER HUMAN BEINGS
DON'T FUCK WITH OTHER
UNLESS THEY WANT TO LOSE EACH OTHER
WELL, YOU JUST LOST ME


ANDY
YOU DON'T CARE HOW I FEEL
SO WHY SHOULD I CARE WHAT I SAY TO YOU?
NO, I THINK YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT OTHER HUMAN BEINGS
DONT FUCK WITH EACH OTHER



(Silence.)

JACK
And now you have nothing to say? (beat) Kay. I'll go.


WILL
Jack- 

JACK
No. It's okay.

(JACK exits)

SKIP
 Why would you say that to him?

 
ANDY
I wasn't calling him that!

SKIP
He's supposed to be one of your best friends and you treat him like he wronged you. He did nothing to you. 

ANDY
Skip -


SKIP
You just fucked up a friendship for all of us because you're too selfish to get that it's not always about YOU!

ANDY
Can I please say something?

SKIP
No! Everything that's coming out of your mouth tonight is shit and I'm tired of listening to you. 

ANDY

You're not listening to me. I would never call him -

WILL
Andy, stop -

ANDY
 No! (to SKIP) It's not about him being gay, Skip, it's about -


MY TURN

WILL
ANDY... THE THING IS
THAT ANDY...

ANDY
IS HE'S THE ONE TALKING
SO SHUT THE FUCK UP

WHY ANDY?
IT'S ALL ABOUT "ANDY"
BUT NOBODY LETS ME SPEAK!
WHEN I'VE BEEN TRYING TO FIT IN 
AND BE LIKE YOU WANT ME TO BE
TRYING TO BE LIKE YOU
BUT I GUESS YOU CANT CHANGE...

SKIP

I DONT REALLY CARE WHEN YOU ARE THAT UNFAIR TO...

WILL
ANDY, PLEASE CALM DOWN, THERE'S...

SKIP and WILL
OTHER HUMAN BEINGS.....

ANDY
THAT INCLUDES ME TOO, YOU GUYS!

YOU CANT JUST ERASE ME
IM SORRY THIS FIGHT HAD TO CHANGE YOUR NIGHT
BUT THE LEAST YOU CAN DO IS FACE ME

YOU CAN'T KEEP LYING TO YOURSELF
AND HOPE YOU'LL FORGET IT
LYING TO KEEP US CLOSE
BUT IT WENT TO SHIT CAUSE YOU LET IT

WILL

Listen -

ANDY
NO! IT IS MY TURN TO LET ME TALK
IF YOU DON'T
I'LL TAKE MY TURN TO TELL THE TRUTH
IF YOU WON'T
IM NOT SAYING JACK WAS WRONG, OR IM THE ONE WHO'S RIGHT
BUT IT IS MY TURN TO SAY MY PIECE TONIGHT


THINGS ARE DIFFERENT WILL
LOOK AROUND
YOUR GOOD OLD GLORY DAYS
 ARE NOWHERE TO BE FOUND 

(ANDY picks up the notebook up off the bleachers)

AND ALL OF THESE MEMORIES WE USED TO ENJOY
THE NIGHTS OUT HERE MAKING TOO MUCH NOISE

THE BROTHERS THAT NO ONE COULD EVER DESTROY
 WERE WORTH NOTHING! NOTHING! NOTHING!!

(ANDY tears the notebook apart.)

WHAT HAPPENED TO MY BOYS?
NOW IT IS MY TURN TO ASK YOU
WHAT TO DO?

WHEN AFTER FIVE YEARS 

I DON'T TRUST YOU
WE'VE BEEN BROTHERS FOR SO LONG
AND THAT'S NO LONGER TRUE - 

SO IT IS MY TURN - 

IT IS MY TURN
TO GO
BUT IT IS YOUR TURN
TO KNOW 

I'VE NEVER HAD A GIFT LIKE YOURS FOR CLEVER WORDS TO SAY
 BUT NOW IT'S MY TURN AND I DONT WANT THEM ANYWAY

(ANDY exits. WILL, near tears, is on the ground, trying to piece together his journal)

SKIP
What was he talking about? You lied to him?

WILL
No. (beat) I lied to him. And Jack. And you.


SKIP
About what?

WILL
Andy told me he wasn't cool with Jack coming out and I told him not to saying anything, cause I didn't want anything to get fucked up. But I fucked it up anyway. (beat) This is all my fault.

SKIP
Oh calm down. The world's not ending. They'll cool off. Maybe they'll even make out, everyone else is doing it. (beat) Why were you guys kissing anyways?  Something you wanna tell me?


WILL
No. I dunno. He kissed me. I just - let it happen.

SKIP
You can't go around trying to please everyone Will.

WILL
I know.
 

(WILL continues to pick up the pieces of the notebook)

SKIP
(beat) It's just a diary. You can always get another one.

(SKIP kneels down to help)

WILL
(smiles) It's not a diary. (beat) Skip...everything I've ever felt was in this thing. 


SKIP
Well, that's not healthy.

WILL
Yeah, maybe not. 

SKIP
Maybe not. (holding the papers in his hand) This stuff was from when we were kids, Will. We've grown up a little since then.


WILL
I know, but when the hell did that happen?

SKIP
 Good question.

BOYS
 
 WILL

WHEN WE WERE BOYS
WE HAD FUN
AND BLAMED MISTAKES ON BEING HUMAN

BUT NOW WE'RE OLD
AND EVEN ONE
WITH GOOD INTENT HAS POWER TO RUIN

YOU KNOW, I'M TRYING TO BE A MAN
BUT THIS IS A PART OF IT THAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND


ALL OF MY MEMORIES FROM BEING A KID
ARE FILLED WITH THE THINGS THAT ALL OF US DID
WHEN WE WERE YOUNGER WE WERE SO SURE
THAT WE'D NEVER STOP BEING BOYS ANYMORE

SKIP
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU THINK IS DEAD
YOU'RE WHINING LIKE YOUR LIFE IS OVER


WILL
IT FEELS THAT WAY

SKIP
BUT NO ONE SAID
YOU CANT SCREW UP WHEN YOU GET OLDER

WILL
WE WERE SO PERFECT TIL TODAY


SKIP
BUT ANDY'S RIGHT
THE GOOD OLD DAYS

WILL and SKIP
NEVER STAY

ALL OF MY MEMORIES FROM BEING A KID
MAY HAVE BEEN CHANGED BY WHAT WE DID
WE AREN'T WORKING LIKE BEFORE

BUT DOES THAT MEAN WE CANT BE BOYS ANYMORE?

WILL
I DON'T LIKE THIS FEELING
THAT I COULD BE LOSING YOU

SKIP
NOBODY IS LOSING
EVERYONE'S JUST GROWING TOO


WILL
WHAT IF THIS WAS NEVER RIGHT
AND IT TOOK US UP UNTIL TONIGHT 
TO REALIZE WE'D BEEN SAVING FACE
AND ADMIT WE ARE OUT OF PLACE

SKIP
DON'T FIGHT TO FIGURE OUT
SOMETHING WE'LL ALL JUST LAUGH ABOUT

ONE DAY

WILL and SKIP
ONE DAY

WILL
I AM NOT READY TO STOP BEING A KID

SKIP
WELL NOBODY SAID THAT WAS WHAT YOU NEEDED


WILL and SKIP
WE'LL NEVER BE WHO WE WERE BEFORE

SKIP
BUT NEVER SAY THAT WE'RE NOT BOYS...

WILL and SKIP (tradeoff)
ANYMORE

ANYMORE
ANYMORE
 
 (A long silence)

SKIP
God I hate this place. Why couldn't we have gone to Andy's and watched Ella Enchanted? (beat) I'm gonna go.  You want a ride?


WILL
No, that's okay.

SKIP
You sure?

WILL
Yeah...I think I'm gonna stay out here a little longer.

SKIP

All right. We're gonna be okay. I promise.

(SKIP starts to exit.)

Oh I almost forgot.

(SKIP pulls a key out of his pocket and tosses it to WILL)

WILL
You found it.


SKIP
Yeah, the closet was unlocked. So... you went on that date for no reason. Just saying. 

WILL
(smiles) Thanks.

(Silence)

SKIP

(beat) Hey. I love you, ok?

WILL
I know. I love you too.

SKIP
(beat) Night buddy.


WILL 
Night man.

(SKIP exits. WILL looks around the field.)

MY NEXT STORY

WILL
LOOK AT THIS FIELD
LOOK AT THIS PERFECT FIELD

WHAT REALLY KEEPS PEOPLE HERE?
THESE WHITE LINES?
NO BOUNDARIES TO HOLD US HERE
EXCEPT FOR MINE

IT MIGHT BE TIME TO TRY AND FIND A DIFFERENT KIND OF STORY 
INSTEAD OF ONE THAT IVE BEGUN BUT CANT SEEM TO COMPLETE
CEPT THIS IS ALL I KNOW AND I DON'T KNOW WHERE ELSE TO GO
OR WHAT ELSE THERE IS TO ME

IF THEY'RE NOT GONNA BE IN MY NEXT STORY

THEY SAY TO WRITE THE THINGS YOU KNOW
WELL THAT I HAVE, AND THERE THEY BLOW
AROUND THIS FIELD, NO WAY TO SEW 
THEM BACK TOGETHER

I WANT TO SAY IM SORRY FOR
MY INDISCRETIONS FROM BEFORE
BUT NO ONE'S HERE TO HEAR ANYMORE

AND BRING US BACK TOGETHER

I DIDN'T WANT TO GET IT
WHEN SHIFTING STARTED TO OCCUR 
I DIDN'T WANT TO LET IT 
MAKE US WHO WE ARE FROM WHO WE WERE 

BUT THERE REALLY WOULD BE SOMETHING GOOD IF I COULD WRITE A STORY
WITH NO CONVERSIONS OF VERSIONS OF MYSELF I HATE TO BE
AND THIS DRAFT THAT I  DO WOULD BE COMPLETELY TRUE

WHICH SEEMS QUITE OVERDUE FOR ME
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN I SEE MY NEXT STORY

LETS SEE
IM MAKING MISTAKES
AND EACH ONE TAKES ME IN A TOTALLY DIFFERENT DIRECTION
IM GETTING LOST
BUT FINDING OUT THE COST OF PUSHING TOO HARD TO MAKE A CONNECTION
WHEN AM I GROWN UP AND WHEN AM I STILL IMMATURE?

WILL I EVER BE MORE THAN JUST UNSURE?
AND WHEN AM I MAN?
AND WHEN I AM WILL I STILL JUST BE DOING THE BEST THAT I CAN

WHEN I WAS THE GLUE THAT HELD US TOGETHER
OBSERVOR, INVENTOR, AND SOLE DOCUMENTOR
CONSTANTLY WATCHING, THE CONSTANT INCENTIVE 
TO KEEP MOVING FORWARD, AND ALWAYS...
REMEMBER...

ALWAYS REMEMBER...
 KEEP MOVING FORWARD AND ALWAYS REMEMBER...

(He throws the pieces of the torn up journal into the air)

I DON'T KNOW HOW BUT STARTING NOW I VOW TO TELL A STORY
THAT TAKES ACCOUNT OF THE AMOUNT OF LIFE I'VE YET TO SEE
BUT STILL CAN FIND A WAY TO SAY "THIS IS EXACTLY WHO I AM TODAY"
AND THIS IS WHAT I SEE

RIGHT HERE IN MY STORY
AND I'LL TELL IT TRUTHFULLY
CAUSE IT'S JUST ME
AND MY NEXT STORY

(The sprinkler system goes off, soaking WILL.)

THE END.

GLORY DAYS






