


    
    
         
             
                SSA 
                By Nick Blaemire and James Gardiner
             
             
                Reading and Concert Libretto
              
            
            August 8 - August 14, 2006
            
             1 
        
    
    
        
            ASS BACKWARDS
            By Nick Blaemire and James Gardiner
        
        


(A night in May; unusually cool out. The Sturmsville High School football field, home of the Sturmsville Stallions. Williamson Henry, 19, enters wearing a jacket and carrying a backpack.)

TURN AROUND
         
         WILL
TURN AROUND
 TURN AWAY FROM TEMPTING ROADS THAT LEAD YOU ASTRAY

 TURN AROUND
 TURN AROUND AND YOU JUST MIGHT BE FOUND
         
TURN AROUND
 TURN AWAY FROM RULES THAT YOU DON'T NEED TO OBEY
 TURN AROUND
 TURN AROUND AND YOU JUST MIGHT BE FOUND

 
(WILL sits down on the bleachers and checks his watch. It's midnight. He opens his backpack and takes out a small notebook. He reads.)

WILL
"The cabinet door had been left unlocked... big mistake. The boys stared in awe at a row of half-filled bottles glistening on the top shelf. Will had been explicitly warned against going anywhere near his father's liquor cabinet. He knew the punishment would be severe, somewhere between grounding and death, but it was a risk he was willing to take. Jack kept an eye on the door, while Skip carefully ascended each shelf and returned with a tall brown bottle. Andy tore away the gold seal and dared Will to take the first sip. Just as Will placed the bottle to his lips, he heard the sound of footsteps trudging down the hall. Jack tried to warn them but it was too late."

(The sound and lights of a car pulling into the parking lot startle Will. He closes his notepad and stuffs it in his backpack. He looks up in anticipation. WILL smiles)
         
         WILL

          TURN AROUND AND YOU'RE HOME
           WITH THE BEST FRIENDS THAT YOU COULD KNOW
           TURN AROUND AND YOU'RE HOME
           WITH WHO LOVES YOU THE MOST
  TURN AROUND AND YOU'RE HOME
  WITH MEMORIES FROM A LIFETIME AGO

  THAT ONLY SEEM TO GROW AND GROW AND GROW
 
 (SKIP THOMAS, 19, enters without WILL noticing and puts his hands over WILL's eyes)
 
 SKIP
 Guess who, shit head?
 

 WILL
 Hey!
 
 (SKIP and WILL hug)
 
 SKIP
 How are you man? It's been a while.

 
 WILL
Tell me about it. What's up with your hair?

 SKIP
You like? I'm letting nature do its thing.
 
WILL

You look like a stoner.
 
(SKIP hits him.)

SKIP
Where is everybody?
 
WILL
They're on their way. So tell me...

 
ARE YOU READY 
 
WILL
ARE YOU READY FOR TONIGHT?
 
SKIP
What?

 
WILL
ARE YOU READY TO MAKE HISTORY? 
RIGHT HERE ON THIS FOOTBALL FIELD 
YOU AND ME 
AND TWO OTHER GUYS 
WHO SHOULD SHOW UP AT ANY TIME 

WHEN EVER THEY DO GET HERE, I'M 
HOPING YOU'RE READY

SKIP
What are we doing?

 WILL
I can't say. 
 

SKIP
Why not? 
 
WILL
I promised Andy I wouldn't tell you anything 'til he got here.
 
SKIP
What are you talking about?


WILL
We have a plan.
 
SKIP
What do you mean a plan?

WILL
You'll see!
WHEN THE TIMING IS RIGHT

 WE ALL WILL BE HERE FINALLY
AND WHEN WE ARE, YOU'LL FINALLY SEE
"WHAT THIS HIGH SCHOOL MEANS TO ME"
 
 SKIP
How bout, like, a little hint?
 
 WILL

Do you wanna ruin the surprise?
 
SKIP
Come on man! Before they get here!
 
WILL
Fine. How do you feel about water rides?

SKIP

Like at amusement parks?

WILL
Yeah. Sort of.

SKIP
Huh?

WILL
DON'T EVEN TRY TO GUESS 

YOU WONT BE ABLE TO 
CAUSE WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO 
IS GONNA DUMBFOUND EVEN YOU

(ANDERSON SCOTT, 19, and JACK RITCHIE, 19, enter, bickering. ANDY is wearing a jacket and carrying a small duffle bag.) 

ANDY
Fuck that, Batman is so much cooler. He's got all those gadgets... 

 
JACK
Superman could pick up an entire planet and drop it on Batman.
 
ANDY
True, but could he stop a Batarang?
 
JACK
He can travel at the speed of light, Andy. You don't think he can get away from a Batarang?


ANDY
You don't know! Will, who'd win in a fight, Batman or Superman?
 
WILL
Who cares? Hey Jack!!
 
JACK
Hey!

 
      (WILL and JACK hug.)
 
ANDY
Who's the hippie?
 
SKIP
Nice to see you too.

 
(SKIP hits ANDY; they hug and start bickering)

WILL (to JACK)
ARE YOU READY FOR TONIGHT?

JACK
I CANT BELIEVE WE'RE BACK OUT HERE
 

WILL
IT'S BEEN AN ENTIRE YEAR

JACK
I GOTTA SAY IT'S PRETTY WEIRD

WILL
HOW WAS LIFE AT SCHOOL?

JACK

PROBABLY THE SAME AS YOU

WILL
THERE IS NO WAY THAT'S TRUE UNLESS YOU ROOMED WITH ANDY TOO.

SKIP
(to ANDY) Don't start again!

ANDY

HOW THE HELL COULD YOU THINK THAT BATMAN 
WOULD LOSE A BATTLE TO A GUY IN TIGHTS?  
HAVEN'T YOU SEEN THOSE GAY RED UNDIES  
HE WEARS OUTSIDE OF HIS PANTS?
 
SKIP
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY YOU'D EVER BEGIN  

TO ARGUE WITH ME, WHEN YOU KNOW YOU'LL NEVER WIN  
BATMAN IS HUMAN AND SUPERMAN'S NOT  
SO WHO'S GONNA DIE IF ONE OF THEM GETS SHOT?
 
ANDY
Huh. That's a good point.
 
WILL

ARE WE READY FOR TONIGHT?

SKIP
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?

WILL
HAVE WE EVER STEERED YOU WRONG?

SKIP
I DUNNO. IT'S BEEN SO LONG.


WILL
JUST GET READY FOR TONIGHT 
AND WHAT A NIGHT IT'S GONNA BE 
YOU AND YOU AND YOU AND ME 
FINALLY

BACK TOGETHER


SKIP
I'VE MISSED YOU GUYS

ANDY (to JACK)
YOU ONLY LIKE SUPERMAN CAUSE HE FLIES
 
WILL
NOW ARE YOU READY FOR

 
ALL GUYS
READY 
FOR TONIGHT  
RIGHT 
HERE!!

SKIP

So what is this mysterious plan?
 
WILL
Well... 
 
(WILL runs over to his bag)

ANDY
Prepare to get your minds blown!

 
(WILL pulls a large set of keys out of his bag and tosses them to SKIP)

 SKIP
Fascinating. What are these?
 
ANDY
They're keys.
 

SKIP
(sarcastic) Thank you.
 
WILL
But not just any keys. They're from maintenance, which means we can get into any room in the school plus that little black box over there.
 
(WILL points to a small black weather box near the player's bench)
 

SKIP
What's in there?
 
WILL
Access to the Sturmsville Stallions Brand New State of the Art... Sprinkler System. 
 
ANDY
Fucking genius!
 

SKIP
(sarcastic) Yea, brilliant. What are we, twelve?

JACK
I thought we were just hanging out tonight.

WILL
No man! We pranked graduation last year. We're doing it again this year!


SKIP
I'd rather just get drunk.

ANDY
You would.

SKIP
So would you!

JACK

How did you even get these?
 
ANDY
We stole 'em.
 
SKIP
How?
 
ANDY

We went into Abby's house and took 'em.
 
JACK
Who?
 
ANDY
Abby!
 
WILL

Her dad's a janitor.
 
SKIP
Which one?

ANDY
The fat one.
 
WILL

Roy.
 
SKIP
I don't remember a Roy.
 
(WILL takes the keys from SKIP)
 
JACK
You made a point to get to know every janitor while you were in school?

 
(WILL walks over to the box and tries each key in the lock.)
 
SKIP
So let me get this straight, you broke into the girl's house!?
 
ANDY
Not exactly. It was much deeper than that.


WILL
They don't need to hear this.
 
ANDY
Oh come on, it's a good story! I hooked her and Will up on a little dinner date. Imagine if you will... Will drives to the house. He's got on a nice shirt. He walks up, rings the doorbell, and there's Abby. And she's looking FINE. She's all ready to go out for a night on the town, but, suddenly Will decides he has to "use the bathroom." (to WILL) Tell Skip what you said.
 
WILL

About what?
 
ANDY
To Abby!
 
WILL
"May I use your bathroom?"
 
ANDY

And BANG, he's in the house! So while Abby's showing him the bathroom, I'm sneaking in the front door. I hide in the closet. Will takes a fake leak, all done, they leave, I pull off some 007 shit, grab the keys, and I'm out like magic.
 
WILL
Andy...?
 
SKIP
Where was her dad during all this?
 
ANDY

He works a night shift over at Grossman's.
 
WILL
Andy...?
 
ANDY
Now seriously, I don't want to toot my own trombone or anything, but you gotta admit that was some impressive shit I pulled off.
 
WILL

(still digging through the keys) Andy, shut up for a second! This won't open.
 
ANDY
What are you talking about?
 
WILL
The box, it won't open.
 

ANDY
You don't have the key.
 
WILL
What?
 
ANDY
I've got it.
 

WILL
What the hell do you think I've been doing over here?
 
ANDY
I don't know. I've been telling a story.
 
WILL
Jesus Christ. Where is it?
 

ANDY
I got it. (searching his pockets) Somewhere.
 
WILL
You better have it!
 
ANDY

I do, don't wet your pants.
 
SKIP
(to WILL) What happened with Abby?
 
ANDY
(sarcastic) Yeah, why don't you tell Skip and Jack "what happened with Abby?"

 
(ANDY finds the key inside one of his cargo pockets.)
 
WILL
Nothing. (to ANDY) Is that it?
 
ANDY

Yeah.
 
(ANDY tosses the key to WILL)
 
SKIP
What was wrong with her?
 
WILL
Nothing. She was fine, I just didn't have any desire to pursue it.

 
ANDY
Cause he's gay.
 
WILL
Shut up! She's only a junior in high school. 
 
ANDY
(sarcastic) Oh, and that's a big step down for you? You didn't have to date the girl. But you missed out on a great opportunity to get some high quality poon. 

 
WILL
I didn't want any poon.
 
ANDY
What are you talking about? Everybody wants poon!
 
WILL
Not that poon.

 
ANDY
What do you mean, "not that poon." When was the last time you got any poon?
 
JACK
Can we stop saying poon?
 
ANDY
Why don't you tell Jack and Skip how many girls you hooked up with this year?

 
WILL
It's not a competition.
 
ANDY
Yes it is! They wanna know.
 
WILL
Nobody cares!

 
ANDY
Come on! How many?
 
WILL
Probably like... 15.
 
SKIP
(amazed) Really?

 
WILL
Yeah, really... maybe even 20.
 
ANDY
Bullshit!
 
WILL
(proudly lying) It's true.

 
ANDY
You are such a fucking liar! (to SKIP and JACK) I've been with him the whole year, he hasn't even talked to 15 girls.
 
WILL
You don't have to talk to 'em when you're doing it.
 

SKIP
He's got a point.
 
ANDY
There's no way you hooked up with that many girls.
 
WILL
Don't be hurt.
 

ANDY
I'm not!
 
WE'VE GOT GIRLS

ANDY
D'YOU EVER WONDER WHERE THE FEMALES GO 
WHEN THERE'S NO ONE AT THE BAR AND ITS LONELY ON THE DANCE FLOOR? 

THEY'RE IN MY BEDROOM I CAN GUARANTEE 
FIGURING OUT HOW TO PLEASE ME

WILL
D'YOU EVER WONDER WHERE HE GETS THIS SHIT 
AND IF ANY OF THE SKANKS THAT HE STALKS BELIEVE A WORD OF IT? 
HE NEVER LEARNED HOW TO BE MR. RIGHT 

IM THE WITH ALL THE HOTTIES IN MY BED AT NIGHT
 
ANDY
DON'T LISTEN TO A WORD HE SAYS 
HE HASN'T BEEN KISSED SINCE TRUTH OR DARE
 
WILL
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT'S TRUE? 

WHEN I'M WITH GIRLS YOU'RE NOT THERE 
IVE LEARNED WHAT THEY WANT TO HEAR 
AND YOU DON'T KNOW CAUSE YOU DON'T CARE 
IVE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS 
IVE FIGURED EM OUT AND GOT EM UP AGAINST THE WALL
 
ANDY

YOU'VE GOT NOTHING AT ALL 
YOU'RE MAKING THIS UP 
YOU'D HAVE TO HIDE IN A WOMEN'S BATHROOM STALL 
TO GET A GIRL NEAR YOUR BALLS

WILL
YOU THINK YOU'RE MANLY BUT THAT'S NOT ENOUGH 

TO GET A GIRL TO WANT YOU YOU'VE GOTTA BE MORE THAN TOUGH 
THEY WANT A LISTENER AND A PERFECT DATE  
THEN THEY'RE SO STUNNED, THEY DON'T NOTICE WHILE YOU FORNICATE
 
ANDY
YOU THINK YOU'RE SOMETHING KNOWING ALL THESE RULES 
BUT YOU CANT DO MUCH BESIDES YOUR RIGHT HAND WITHOUT THE TOOLS 

GIRLS WANT A BODY THAT IS BIG AND STRONG 
AND UNLESS YOU'VE GOT A PENIS PUMP YOU KNOW HAVENT GOT IT LONG 
IVE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS 
IM GETTING EM HOT CAUSE THEY LIKE IT WHEN THEY'RE GUYS ARE TALL
 
WILL
YOU'VE GOT SOME KIND OF GALL 

BUT NO KIND OF BRAIN 
THE STEROIDS YOU'RE ON MAKE YOUR VITAL ORGANS SMALL 
LIKE THE ONE NEXT TO YOUR BALLS
 
ANDY
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
 
WILL

THE DORK WHO WENT AND RAISED THE BAR
 
ANDY
YOU WISH YOU HAD MY LOOKS
 
WILL
AND YOU WISH YOU COULD READ A BOOK
 
ANDY AND WILL

YOU ARE THE OPPOSITE OF ME
IM MORE THAN HAPPY TO AGREE

WILL
If you've hooked up with so many girls, why are you always jerking off?
 
ANDY
Cause your Mom is constantly on my mind.
 

WILL
Shut up!
 
ANDY
Yeah buddy! She likes it forwards, backwards, sideways... and she loves a good old fashioned Donkey Punch!
 
WILL
I'm gonna kill you!
 

SKIP
Hey hey hey cut it out!
 
(SKIP pulls ANDY off of WILL. JACK helps WILL off the ground)

JACK
You guys haven't changed a bit.
 
ANDY

You're right, Will's still a lying sack of shit!
 
WILL
At least I have a sack! Pussy.
 
(ANDY is enraged, and rushes at WILL. SKIP holds him back.)

SKIP
Knock it off!

 
JACK
I don't see why you're fighting. You both want the same thing. It's like you're competing to see who's the biggest asshole.
 
WILL
Hey!
 
ANDY
(hurt) Shut up!

 
JACK
You guys have no respect for women. I mean, don't you two want nice, sane things? Like love?

ANDY
OF COURSE WE WANT TO BE IN LOVE 
AND WE'RE LOOKING FOR ROMANCE

WILL

BUT TIL WE FIND THAT LONESOME DOVE

ANDY
WE'LL JUST GET INTO THEIR PANTS

ANDY AND WILL
WE'VE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS 
THEY'RE LOOKIN FOR LOVE BUT THAT'S NOT WHAT WE'RE MAKIN AT ALL 
WE'VE GOT GIRLS BY THE BALLS AND WE'RE HOLDIN ON 

IT'S TIME FOR EVERY GIRL TO BE GRABBED 
BY THE BALLS!

JACK
Well, I'm glad to see you guys have grown up.
 
ANDY
Oh... things grew. (points to his crotch)  Like my dong! (laughs)

 
SKIP
You're an idiot.
 
JACK
I can't believe you guys lived in the same room.
 
WILL
It was hard sometimes. (points to ANDY) He never showers.

 
ANDY
Shut up dude!
 
WILL
Maybe once a week.
 
JACK
I'm just glad I didn't have to live with you guys.

 
WILL
Hey! Can you imagine if the four of us had actually lived together? I mean, if we all went to the same school?
 
JACK
People would have died.
 
ANDY
Whatever, that would have been tight! The four of us in a suite, trading bitches like Pokemon cards.

 
WILL
Seriously though, think of all the shit we could have pulled off.
 
SKIP
Yeah right. On a college campus? We would've gotten expelled so fast.
 
WILL
At least it would've been a challenge. 

 
SKIP
You don't think this'll be a challenge?
 
WILL
This? (WILL waves the key in the air and heads towards the box) This'll be a breeze!

SKIP

We'll see.
 
WILL
What's that supposed to mean?
 
SKIP
I don't think it'll be that easy.
 
WILL

It's gonna be great! Why do you always have to get so skeptical?
 
SKIP
I do not!
 
WILL
Yeah you do! I thought you were gonna have an aneurism when we stole the diplomas from Covington's office last year.
 
SKIP

That was my idea!
 
ANDY
Yeah, but you were sweatin' beads the whole time.  "I dunno guys, maybe we should abort..." Who says abort? We're not in a Star Trek Movie!
 
(WILL opens the box.)
 
WILL
We're in!

 
ANDY
(to SKIP) See!? (looks in the box) Oooo, this is fancy. (reaches into the box)
 
WILL
Don't touch. (smacks ANDY's hand) Let's see, we've got... Start Time, Run Time -

 
SKIP (to WILL)
We're really gonna do this?
 
WILL
Yeah, we're really gonna do this... what's your deal?
 
SKIP

Whatever.
 
WILL
(like pulling teeth) What!?
 
SKIP
Come on, what do you want to accomplish by screwing with their sprinkler system?
 

WILL
What do you mean? This is the plan!
 
SKIP
I know, and I think it's stupid.
 
ANDY
Oh shit... it's got a little computer screen.
 

WILL
Don't touch! (smacks ANDY's hand again. To SKIP) Why did you even bother coming then?
 
SKIP
I didn't know we were pulling a prank! I wanted to see you guys.
 
WILL

But this is what we do every year. It's tradition.
 
SKIP
We've done it once. I don't think that qualifies as a tradition.
 
WILL
Well they've gotta start somewhere.
 
SKIP

This is retarded.
 
ANDY
Dude, just go home! We don't need your negative ass dragging everything down. The three of us can handle this by ourselves.
 
JACK
I don't know. I'm not really feeling it either.
 
WILL

What? Come on guys this is important!
 
JACK
How? What exactly do we get out of this?
 
ANDY
For starters, it's funny as fuck.
 
SKIP

It's also illegal.
 
WILL
No! It sends a message.
 
SKIP
Which one's that?
 
WILL

That we deserve respect.
 
SKIP
By drenching an entire field of people you think the school's going to start respecting us?
 
WILL
It'll make 'em listen.
 
SKIP

They won't even know we did it!
 
WILL
But we'll know.
 
SKIP
Great, so what message does that send?
 
WILL

That we know who we are despite what other people think of us. That's the reason we became friends in the first place, isn't it?
 
JACK
No, the reason we became friends was because we didn't care what other people thought of us.
 
WILL
Right, we don't care.
 
SKIP

But don't you see that by doing this, your showing that you do!
 
WILL
No!
 
ASS BACKWARDS

WILL
WHEN YOU WERE YOUNG 

DIDN'T YOU HAVE DREAMS THAT YOU LET GO OF 
CAUSE SOMEBODY TOLD YOU THAT YOU WEREN'T ALLOWED TO DREAM 
THE WAY YOU DO JUST CAUSE YOU WERE DIFFERENT?
  
ANDY
YEA, AND WHO WERE THEY

ALL THOSE ASSHOLES WHO MESSED WITH US 

THEY NEVER GOT THE BEST OF US 
THEY WEREN'T READY TO LET ME BE WHAT IM GONNA BE SO FUCK EM 
IF THEY'RE DIFFERENT THAN ME

SKIP
BUT WE ARE STILL YOUNG 
AND THOUGH WE MAY HAVE TRIED TO RID OUR LIVES 

OF THE COOL PEOPLE'S BULLSHIT 
THE BRUISES TO PROVE THAT IT STUNG ARE STILL HERE 
CAUSE WE'RE STILL DIFFERENT

JACK
SO PLEASE LET'S LET IT BE 
CAUSE IF WE HAVENT LET THIS GO 

WE WONT MOVE ON AND WE'LL NEVER GROW 
AND IM NOT READY TO BE PROUDLY FAKE FOR OLD TIMES SAKE 
IM DIFFERENT 
BUT IM NOT THE OLD ME
 
WILL
LISTEN, LIFE'S NOT FAIR 

AND WHO KNOWS WHY PEOPLE CHANGE AND PEOPLE LIE 
BUT WE DON'T HAVE TO BE THEM WE DON'T HAVE TO ROLL OVER AND DIE 
WE CAN TRY 
TO BE ASS BACKWARDS 
AND GO AGAINST THE GRAIN FROM BEING SO NORMAL 
THAT IT MAKES YOU GO INSANE


WILL and ANDY
BECAUSE ASS BACKWARDS 
IS SEEING OUR LIVES THROUGH DIFFERENT ANGLES 
EACH OTHER'S EYES

SKIP
Will, this whole thing is really childish.
 

WILL
You didn't think that last year.
 
SKIP
That prank was stupid too. The next day they printed out new copies of the diplomas.
 
ANDY
Yeah, but they didn't have them for the ceremony.
 

SKIP
So? Those assholes still graduated. The world didn't spin off its axis. It was a minor inconvenience at best.
 
JACK
Plus we could've been expelled for that.
 
WILL
But we weren't! Come on, what happened to you guys? You used to love shit like this!
 

SKIP
YOU THINK YOU'LL NEVER CHANGE 
AND YOU'LL NEVER REARRANGE THIS PERFECT PICTURE 
BUT YOU'LL MOVE AWAY AND THOUGH YOU PRAY THAT THEY'LL STAY 
THE GOOD OLD DAYS SAY GOODBYE AND SUDDENLY YOU'RE DIFFERENT

WILL AND ANDY
LISTEN, LIFE'S NOT FAIR 

CAUSE TIME GOES BY 
PEOPLE CHANGE AND DREAMS GO DRY 
BUT WE DON'T HAVE TO LET THEM 
WE CAN'T FORGET TO LIVE AND THEN DIE

WILL
Come on guys. It's only the sprinklers.
 

ALL
(WILL starts as the others join in gradually)
WE CAN TRY 
TO BE ASS BACKWARDS AND RISE ABOVE THE REST 
AND BE ASS BACKWARDS INSTEAD OF BEING THE BEST 
ASS BACKWARDS IS SEEING OUR LIVES FROM DIFFERENT ANGLES 
EACH OTHER'S EYES

 
BEING ASS BACKWARDS 
AND LEARNING FROM OUR FRIENDS THAT BEING ASS BACKWARDS 
MEANS FRIENDSHIP NEVER ENDS 
ASS BACKWARDS IS SEEING OUR LIVES FROM DIFFERENT ANGLES 
EACH OTHER'S EYES
 

WILL
So?
 
SKIP
Alright. Fine, let's do it.
 
WILL
Great!
 

(They all run over to the box)
 
(looking into the box) Let's see. Tomorrow is....?
 
JACK
Thursday.
 
WILL

Right. Okay. It's set to go off at... 1:30 tonight.
 
ANDY
Graduation starts at 2:00 tomorrow.
 
WILL
So we'll set it for 2:30! Sound good?
 
SKIP

Works for me.
 
WILL
2:30 it is. (Starts punching in numbers) Hour...2.... (Pause) Hour...2.  Shit!!
 
SKIP

What?
 
WILL
It's got a password.
 
ANDY
No it doesn't!
 
WILL

Yes, Andy, it clearly does.
 
ANDY
Where?
 
WILL
There, where it says "password."
 
(ANDY stares at the screen. Silence)


You don't have it, do you?
 
ANDY
I didn't fucking know there was one! (beat) Why don't you just type in Stallions or something?
 
(ANDY reaches into the box)
 

WILL
No! (smacks ANDY's hand away) It's not going to be that simple. They're not idiots. For starters, the pad doesn't even have letters. It's just digits.
 
ANDY
Well let's start typing in numbers.
 
SKIP

That's dumb.
 
ANDY
You've got a better idea?
 
SKIP
Look, why don't we just go over to Jack's house and watch a movie?
 
JACK

No -
 
ANDY
Oooo... We can watch Channel 85!
 
WILL
I'd rather not spend my evening watching scrambled porn. Look, we can figure this out. We've got the whole night.
 
ANDY

The whole night!?
 
WILL
Yeah! That's what we agreed on.
 
ANDY
Oh...
 
WILL

What is your problem?
 
ANDY
I agree with Skip. Numbers and.... I don't think we're gonna be able to figure this out tonight. Let's just go to Jack's.
 
JACK
I'm glad everyone's inviting themselves over to my house.
 
ANDY

Besides I'm supposed to meet up with Beth later.
 
WILL
No way!!
 
ANDY
Excuse me?
 
WILL

You can screw around with Beth or anybody else you want the rest of the summer. Tonight is about us.
 
ANDY
But...
 
WILL
(resigned) No - this is more important.
 

ANDY
Will...
 
WILL
No, Andy. I said no!!
 
(Silence. SKIP and JACK are in awe. Will takes his cell phone out of his pocket and tosses it to ANDY)
 
Tell her you can't make it.


ANDY
She's gonna be pissed. I made plans with her like a week ago.
 
WILL
Yeah? Well we've been planning this for a month... so call her, deal with it and let's start having a fucking good time!
 
SKIP
(taken aback. sotto voce) Yes sir...

 
ANDY
Well, what am I supposed to say?
 
WILL
I don't care. Say you have more important things to do. Say your car blew up on the way over and you're dead. It doesn't matter. She'll believe whatever you say. She's dumb as shit anyway.
 
ANDY
Fine. But maybe you should call her.

 
WILL
I will if you want!
 
(JACK laughs)
 
ANDY
Screw you!
 

(WILL starts to call Chelsea)

No. I'll do it!
 
(ANDY takes the phone away from WILL, moves upstage)
 
WILL
Idiot.

SKIP

(to WILL) So what do you wanna do?
 
WILL
Just let me think.
 
(Silence)
 
JACK

The password has to be written down somewhere, right?
 
SKIP
Maybe, but how would we get that?
 
JACK
Well, this is the master key to the building, isn't it?
 
WILL

Yeah.
 
SKIP
So?
 
JACK
So it'll get us into the maintenance closet. And I bet you twenty bucks the password's in there. (beat) Look, it has to be written down. Those guys can't even count to 10, how are they gonna remember a password? I mean it's worth trying! We're running out of ideas.

 
ANDY
(upstage, still talking on the phone) I know. It was terrible. The whole thing just blew up. It was probably a faulty engine- I don't know. Yeah I'm alive. I just broke a few bones. Alright listen, I gotta run - but I'll call you tomorrow. Bye babe.
 
(ANDY turns off his phone and crosses downstage to the guys.)
 
ANDY
All right! So what's the plan?

 
(SKIP just shakes his head at ANDY)

What?
 
SKIP
(to WILL) Here, give me the keys. I'll go see what I can find. Twenty bucks.
 

(WILL gives the keys to SKIP. SKIP exits.)
 
ANDY
Where's he going?
 
WILL
To see if he can find the password.
 
ANDY

Good idea. (beat) Hey, I almost forgot. Do either of you want a beer? It's not the best stuff, but it's all I could find.
 
(ANDY runs over to the bleachers. He pulls a couple bottles out of his bag.)

WILL
(to ANDY) What kind did you get?
 

ANDY
Blankson's Brew.
 
JACK
Did you steal those from your Dad's fridge?
 
ANDY
Yup.
 

JACK
That's sad.
 
ANDY
(to JACK) You want one?
 
JACK
That's all right.

 
WILL
No, thanks.
 
ANDY
I know you don't want one. You fuckin' pussy.
 
(ANDY and JACK both laugh and ANDY takes a sip of his beer)
 

ANDY
(to JACK) So how was school, man?
 
JACK
I don't know.
 
ANDY
That's it...I don't know?? You've been away for 7 months and that's all you got?

  
WILL
How was your roommate?
 
JACK
He was fine. I only had to put up with him for a little while.
 
ANDY
Did he get kicked out?

 
JACK
No
 
ANDY
Cause this kid on our floor got kicked out for smoking weed in his room. He was a smart kid too... he tried to create this ventilation system out his window, so the RA couldn't smell it. But someone saw the smoke outside and called the fire department. Now he goes to community college. Fuckin' sucks.
 
(Silence)
 

WILL (to JACK)
How were your grades last semester?
 
JACK
Umm...ok. (pause) I actually left before the semester ended.
 

WILL
What?
 
JACK
Yeah, so I didn't get grades.
 
ANDY
Woah, woah, woah, hold the phone... What'd you do?
 

JACK
I decided to leave.
 
WILL
You just left?
 
JACK
Yeah.
 

ANDY
What'd you do?
 
JACK
I took a road trip.
 
ANDY
GET OUT!
 

JACK
Yeah.
 
ANDY
That's awesome! You meet any hot bitches?
 
JACK
Not really.
 

WILL
Why didn't you tell us?
 
JACK
I don't know. It wasn't a big deal.
 
ANDY
Are you shitting me?! That's huge!
 

WILL
How long were you gone?
 
JACK
A little over a month... I got back about two weeks ago.
 
WILL
Wait... you've been home for two weeks? We've been here since the 3rd. Why didn't you call us? 
 

JACK
I don't know.
 
WILL
Did you not want us to know?
 
JACK
No, Will, I wasn't trying to keep anything from you. I just needed some time to myself.
 

ANDY
Well, I wanna know everything! Where did you go? What did you do? Who'd ya bang? Tell me everything!
 
JACK
Everything?
 
ANDY
Yeah.
 

JACK
Okay...

THE OPEN ROAD

JACK
SO I TOOK A MONTH OFF FROM SCHOOL 
AND DECIDED TO GO ON A TRIP 
I PACKED MY BAGS AND KISSED MY MOM GOODBYE

 
ANDY
You kissed your Mom? Gross...
 
JACK
AND I GOT INTO MY CAR 
WHAT A LOUSY PIECE OF SHIT 
BUT I DIDN'T CARE 

I JUST NEEDED TO TRY 
AND GO DRIVING DOWN THE COAST 
IN THE NICE DAYS OR THE RAIN 
I WORE THE SAME CLOTHES AND GOT FOOD ON THE GO 
I TORE AROUND THOSE CURVES 
JUST SPEEDING THROUGH THE PLAINS 

SOMETIMES I WENT SO FAST I WANTED TO EXPLODE 
CAUSE IT WAS JUST ME 
AND THE OPEN ROAD
 
I STOPPED AT ALL THE PARKS 
AND SLEPT UNDER THE SKY 
AND WHEN I WOKE I DROVE THE REST OF THE DAY 

I TOOK SHORTCUTS THROUGH PEOPLES' YARDS 
AND RAN MY GAS TANK CLOSE TO DRY 
AND WHEN I SPED BY COPS I KNEW JUST WHAT TO SAY 
AFTER THE FOURTEENTH TIME 
WHEN I WAS DRIVING THROUGH THE EAST 
WITH THE WINDOWS ROLLED DOWN LOW 

THERE WAS SO MUCH AIR THAT I COULD HARDLY BREATHE 
I TAUGHT MYSELF THE LAND FROM THE BLUE RIDE TO POCONOS 
I BECAME AN EXPERT ON HOW TRAFFIC FLOWED 
I LOVED MY LIFE ALONE 
ON THE OPEN ROAD
 
AND THEN I MET THIS BOY AT A TRUCK STOP IN DES MOINES 

HE WOULDN'T HITCH CAUSE HE HAD TOO MUCH PRIDE 
SO HE ASKED ME FOR A RIDE
 
AND WE LEARNED EACH OTHER'S LAUGHS 
AS WE TALKED ALL THROUGH THE NIGHT 
AND WHEN HE THOUGHT THE TIME WAS RIGHT 
HE KISSED ME IN THE CAR BENEATH A STARLESS SKY 

AND WITH THAT KISS HE OPENED UP MY MIND 
AND WE WENT DRIVING 
WE WERE DRIVING 
WE WERE DRIVING 
JUST ME 
A BEAUTIFUL BOY 

AND THE OPEN ROAD
 
(Silence)
 
WILL
Have you told your parents yet?
 
JACK
Yup.

 
WILL
What did they say?
 
JACK
My mom said she always knew...
 
WILL
So did I.

 
JACK
...which was so annoying.
 
WILL
Oh. Sorry.
 
JACK
That's okay.

 
WILL
(pause) Well that's.... great. Wow. I'm sorry. I'm just...I'm really proud of you.
 
(WILL hugs JACK)

JACK
Thanks.

 
WILL
Think of it this way, you've already got three great boyfriends. And best of all we split up the duties! That way you'll never get sick of one guy. Skip gives you thought provoking conversation, I organize your day, and Andy gives it to you up the butt.
 
ANDY
Stop.
 
WILL
I was just joking.

 
ANDY
It wasn't funny.
 
(SKIP enters)

SKIP
Hey! (to JACK) You owe you me twenty bucks! I didn't find shit. (He hands the keys back to WILL. He raises a magazine.) But I did find this Hustler in the closet? It's a classic. Check out the banana titties on page 42. (Tosses the magazine to Jack. Silence) What?

 
JACK
I'm gay.
 
(Silence)
 
SKIP
(He starts to laugh, but realizes that it's not a joke) Really?

 
JACK
Yeah, I just - you missed it.
 
SKIP
Oh. Wow. You don't need to hold that. (Takes the magazine from JACK and tosses it) So you're gay? I sort of always knew I think, no offense, you're just not very good at hiding things.
 

JACK
Thanks.
 
SKIP
You're welcome. (silence. SKIP just stares at JACK) I'm sorry. It's just... new.
 
JACK

For me too.
 
SKIP
But it's great!
  
JACK
Thanks.
 
(JACK looks over at ANDY)

 
JACK
Is this going to be okay?
 
SKIP
Of course.
 
JACK
I just don't want anything to change.

 
WILL
It won't. 

JACK
(Noticing that ANDY hasn't said anything, he decides to change the subject. To WILL) So what's the plan?
 
WILL

Umm - I don't know. (to SKIP) You didn't see anything?
 
SKIP
Nope.
 
WILL
Did you check each of the closets?

 
SKIP
Each?
 
WILL
Yeah. There's one in each floor.
 
SKIP
How the hell was I supposed to know that!?

 
JACK
That's okay. (to SKIP) Let's go look in the other ones.
 
SKIP
Fine. (to WILL) Each floor!? Is there anything else I should know? Is there some mystical passage way I don't know about?

 
WILL
No.
 
SKIP
All right! Let's go.
 
(SKIP and JACK exit. Long silence)
 

WILL
(to ANDY) Hello?
 
(Silence)

WILL
Are you okay?
 

ANDY
I'm fine.
 
WILL
You don't look fine.
 
ANDY
(beat) I don't understand why you're okay with this.

 
WILL
I'm sorry?
 
ANDY
This doesn't bother you?
 
WILL
Why would it?

 
THINGS ARE DIFFERENT
 
ANDY
HOW CAN YOU IGNORE 
HE IS NOT THE SAME 
TO SAY THAT I LOVED HIM ALMOST SOUNDS PROFANE 

YOU SAY THAT YOU DON'T CARE 
BUT HOW CAN YOU NOT 
HE LIED TO ALL OF US 
THAT MATTERS A LOT 
JACK IS GONE 
NOW THERE'S ONLY FAIRY DUST 

HE WONT BELONG AS LONG AS IM A PART OF US
 
WILL
SO GO
 
ANDY
CAUSE JACK MEANS MORE THAN ME?
 
WILL

NO 
CAUSE I JUST DON'T AGREE 
THAT JACK HAS TO LEAVE NOW THAT HE'S OPENED UP 
HE'S OUR BEST FRIEND, DON'T WE ASK THAT OF HIM? 
WE DON'T HAVE THE RIGHT TO SAY THAT HE'S NOT ALLOWED  
TO OPEN UP "THAT WAY" 

OKAY?

ANDY
NO 
I CAN'T PRETEND NOT TO CARE 
I LOOK AND MY FRIEND ISNT THERE 
I DON'T LIKE BEING LIED TO 

HOW CAN YOU? 
WHEN THINGS GO WRONG 
YOU ALWAYS SEE THE UPSIDE 
WHY?
 
WILL
CAUSE I CAN STILL SEE HIM WHEN I LOOK AT HIS FACE 

HE'S NOT ANY DIFFERENT, HE'S JUST IN A DIFFERENT PLACE 
WHY CANT YOU SEE THAT? 
PEOPLE ARE ALLOWED TO CHANGE 
WHY GREET THAT CHANGE BY CAUSING HIM PAIN?
 
ANDY
IM NOT TRYING TO HURT HIM

 
WILL
BUT CAN'T YOU SEE THAT YOU ARE?
 
ANDY
LOOK, THIS ISNT MY BURDEN
 
WILL
IF YOU'RE HIS FRIEND, THEN YOU'D BETTER START


         

    
      
    
    
      
    	
  

    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
WILL
UNDERSTANDING 
I THOUGHT YOU HAD A HEART

 ANDY
UNDERSTAND ME 
THIS COULD TEAR US APART


WILL
THIS ISNT WRONG, ANDY THIS IS JUST NEW 
YOU CANT HATE JACK CAUSE HE'S DIFFERENT THAN YOU
 
ANDY
DONT MAKE IT SOUND LIKE IVE DONE SOMETHING WRONG 
I HAVE MY FEELINGS, AND I DON'T THINK HE BELONGS




  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
   
WILL
 THIS ISN'T WRONG ANDY, THIS IS JUST NEW 
 HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT YOU CANT LOVE HIM 
 JACK NEVER SAID THAT YOU HAD TO LIVE 
 YOUR LIFE ONE WAY 
LET GO OF YOUR BIAS, HE IS YOUR FRIEND  
OR THIS COULD BE

ANDY
 THINGS ARE DIFFERENT, WILL 
THINGS HAVE CHANGED 
JACK IS NO LONGER WITH US 
ONLY THE BODY REMAINS 
NOW ITS JUST YOU AND ME  
AND SKIP. ONE TWO THREE

WILL AND ANDY
NOT FOUR ANYMORE

WILL

So you're willing to throw away everything. Just like that!
 
ANDY
I guess so.
 
(JACK and SKIP enter unseen by WILL and ANDY.)

WILL
Why is this such a problem for you?

 
ANDY
Because he lied! Because he's been lying to us for the past 8 years!
 
WILL
Jesus... this is so twisted! He didn't lie to us!
 
ANDY
Fine, think whatever you want. I'm leaving!

 
(ANDY grabs his jacket off the player's bench)

WILL
Andy. I think if you just talk to him -

ANDY
No Will! I don't need to do anything. This is his issue. Not mine.
 
WILL

No! You're the one who's making this an issue.
 
ANDY
This isn't about me!
 
WILL
This is about you. This is all about you. You're the one who's being a fucking asshole!
 
ANDY

No! You know what fuck you! Go ahead and have fun with your little faggot friend.
 
(ANDY starts to exit and sees JACK and SKIP standing by the bleachers. SKIP steps forward to say something to ANDY but JACK stops him)
 
OTHER HUMAN BEINGS

JACK (to ANDY)
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS 

YOU NEVER DO TO OTHER HUMAN BEINGS 
LIKE WHAT I OVERHEARD 
YOU JUST SAY ABOUT ME

BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND, DO YOU? 
I MEAN, OTHER HUMAN BEINGS 
WE DON'T ALL WALK AROUND 

SAYING WHATEVER WE WANT
 
CAUSE WE HAVE THE ABILITY TO CHOOSE 
WHAT WE MAKE A PERSON FEEL 
TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR WHO YOU LOSE 
WHEN THE PAIN YOU INFLICT BECOMES REAL
 

SO BEFORE YOU GO, YOU SHOULD KNOW 
THAT OTHER HUMAN BEINGS 
DONT FUCK WITH EACH OTHER 
UNLESS THEY WANT TO LOSE EACH OTHER 
AND YOU JUST LOST ME
 
(JACK waits for ANDY to say something. ANDY remains silent.)

 
JACK
And now you have nothing to say.
 
ANDY
You came here tonight and dropped this shit on us...and assumed that everything would be fine.
 
SKIP
Why are you being such a dick?

 
ANDY
Mind your own fucking business!
 
WILL
Okay, enough.
 
SKIP
Where do you get off talking to him like that?

  
ANDY
I don't have to listen to this. I'm leaving!

(ANDY starts to exit)

SKIP
Good!
 
ANDY

Yeah, have a great time without me. You fuckin' prick!
 
WILL
(grabs ANDY by the arm) Just wait a minute! You need to talk about this.
 
ANDY
There's nothing to talk about. I'm going home!
 

(WILL grabs ANDY's arm)
 
WILL
(with a huge outburst) NO YOU'RE NOT! (Silence) We've been friends for 8 years. I'm not letting you throw that away just because we haven't seen each other for a few months. We can fix this. Just forget about it.
 
FORGET ABOUT IT


WILL
WHEN YOU WERE YOUNG 
REMEMBER THOSE DREAMS THAT YOU LET GO OF 
CAUSE SOMEBODY TOLD YOU  
THAT YOU WEREN'T ALLOWED TO DREAM THE WAY YOU DO 
DIDN'T YOU

 
AND NOW EVERYTHING IS ASS BACKWARDS 
AND WE SEE EACH OTHER THROUGH DIFFERENT EYES 
EVERYTHING IS ASS BACKWARDS 
AND WE'RE BECOMING PEOPLE WE DESPISE 
SO WHY NOT TRY AND FORGET ABOUT IT?
 

FORGET ABOUT IT 
WHEN YOU SEE ALL THE INCONSISTENSIES IN THE WAY WE SEE THE WORLD 
FORGET ABOUT IT 
WHEN YOU LEARN THAT SOMEONE YEARNS TO BE DIFFERENT
 
THINGS CAN CHANGE 
BUT THINGS CANNOT GO AWRY 

SO FORGET ABOUT IT 
AND MOVE ON 
ALL RIGHT?
 
ALL RIGHT?

SKIP
ALL RIGHT


WILL (to JACK)
ALL RIGHT?
 
JACK
ALL RIGHT
 
WILL (to ANDY)

ALL RIGHT?
 
ANDY
IT'S NOT THAT EASY, WILL

WILL
YES IT IS 
PEOPLE CHANGE 

AND PEOPLE LIE 
PEOPLE TRY TO SAVE A FRIENDSHIP 
IS IT SO HARD  
TO SEE WHY 
AND TURN AROUND FOR ANOTHER TRY? 
JUST FORGET ABOUT IT 

COME ON GUYS
 
WILL
FORGET ABOUT IT
 
SKIP, WILL
FORGET ABOUT IT
 



    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  

    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
    
      
    
    
      
    	
  
  
SKIP, WILL, JACK
FORGET ABOUT IT 
FORGET ABOUT IT 
FORGET ABOUT IT

ANDY
IT'S NOT THAT EASY 
WHATEVER YOU SAY 
FINE, WE'LL JUST...
 		
ALL
FORGET ABOUT IT
 
WILL
ALL RIGHT?
 
 (ANDY rushes out. WILL goes after him)


WILL
Andy!
 
JACK
What did I do wrong?
 
SKIP
Nothing.

 
JACK
Then why is he acting like this!?  I'm not trying to fuck things up!
 
SKIP
I know.
 
JACK
He's such an asshole.

 
SKIP
Are you really surprised?
 
JACK
What do you mean?
 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY


SKIP
HE'S NEVER BEEN LIKE US 
YOU'VE ALWAYS KNOWN THAT 
SO THE FACT THAT HE'D CHANGE AT THE DROP OF A HAT 
SHOULD NOT BE SURPRISING	 
CAUSE IT'S ALWAYS BEEN CLEAR 

THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT HIM THAT WON'T LET US NEAR
 
ANDY  
THE THING ABOUT ANDY 
IS HOW CLOSE WE ARE TO HIM 
AND HOW MUCH WE STILL DON'T KNOW

ANDY 

THE THING ABOUT ANDY 
IS HOW MUCH HE'S HOLDING BACK 
LIKE IT'LL HURT TO LET GO 
SO HE MAY NEVER SHOW 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY

JACK

MAYBE 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY 
IS HE DOESN'T KNOW HIMSELF 
THE WAY THAT HIS BEST FRIENDS DO 
MAYBE 
THE TRUTH IS THAT ANDY 

JUST ISNT AS SMART AS US 
SO HOW CAN WE EXPECT HIM TO?
 
SKIP
OR MAYBE THAT'S NOT TRUE 
AND WE DON'T KNOW ANDY 
BUT HOW CAN THAT BE? 

HE'S STILL THE PERSON WHO 
WE STOOD NEXT TO SINCE WE WERE KIDS
 
JACK
BUT OBVIOUSLY 
THE BEST FRIEND THAT I ONCE KNEW 
WOULD NEVER DO WHAT HE JUST DID

 
SKIP AND JACK
ITS EMBARASSING THAT WE 
CAN LOOK SO HARD 
AND STILL NOT SEE A THING 
ABOUT
 

SKIP
ANDY 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY 
IS WE MAY HAVE LET HIM DOWN 
AND THAT CANT BE UNDONE
 
JACK

ANDY 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY 
HAS PUSHED HIM AWAY FROM US 
BEFORE WE HAD BEGUN
 
SKIP AND JACK
TO FINALLY LEARN ONE 

THING ABOUT ANDY

 SKIP
I don't think any of us know each other as well as we think we do.
 
JACK
I think I know you pretty well.
 
SKIP

Sure, but you don't know everything.
 
JACK
Okay fine, but I feel like I know something about you. I don't feel like I know anything about Andy. It's like he's a completely different person. Like something got added on or taken away. That's not the same kid I grew up with.
 
SKIP
And that's exactly the way he feels about you. You're not the same person either. You've changed. We all change.
 
JACK

Thanks Socrates. Some of us change for the better. I think Andy's regressed.
 
SKIP
Look, this is gonna work itself out. I don't think he meant to say the things he did. Just give him some time to cool off, then you two can talk. He'll come around.
 
JACK
I hope so.
 
(Silence)

 
SKIP
So is there a guy?
 
JACK
Excuse me?
 
SKIP
Like a guy? Like a boyfriend guy?

 
JACK
Yeah.
 
SKIP
Is that what you call it?
 
JACK
(laughs) Sure, you can call it that.

 
SKIP
Who is he?
 
JACK
His name's Michael.
 
SKIP
Michael! Did you meet him at school?

 
JACK
No. I actually took some time off at the end of the semester, and met him while I was in Iowa.
 
SKIP
Iowa?

JACK
Yea. I took a road trip for a month.

 
SKIP
Really!?
 
JACK
Yea.
 
SKIP
Where did you go?

 
JACK
As far as I could get on the money I had, which wasn't much. I hit like 11 states I think.
 
SKIP
Including Iowa. Wow. Why did you decide to do that?
 
JACK
I don't know. I wanted a change. There was...stuff I needed to figure out.

 
SKIP
So you dropped everything and just... left?
 
JACK
Yea.
 
(WILL enters behind the bleachers. He is unseen by JACK and SKIP)


SKIP
I can't believe you did that. I wish I had taken that kind of time to put things in perspective for myself. I feel like I'm stuck, like I want to jump start something but I don't know how to make that happen.
 
JACK
Neither does Andy. .
 
SKIP
Or Will. Especially Will! He hasn't changed at all. In fact he's in a perpetual battle against change. It's like he wants us to be the same friends we were in high school, and we're not. I mean what in the world made him think that this prank was a good idea?"
 

JACK
I don't know.
 
SKIP
It's like, grow up already.

AFTER ALL

WILL
WHEN I FEEL ALONE, I HAVE THESE FRIENDS OF MINE 

THE OTHER HALVES OF ME, WHO KEEP ME SANE IN TROUBLED TIMES 
AND WHEN I LOSE MY WAY, I HAVE THEM THERE IN THE BACK OF MY MIND 
AND THEN I DON'T FEEL LONELY AFTER ALL
 
WHEN I WAS YOUNG, I ONLY HAD MYSELF 
TO GUIDE MY LIFELESS ACTION FIGURES TO THE FLOOR, DOWN FROM THE SHELF 
MY BEDROOM WAS MY PLAYGROUND TO DRAW AND WRITE AND PRAY 

THAT I WOULD FIND A REAL FRIEND TO GUIDE ME SOMEDAY 
AND NOW
 
WHEN I FEEL ALONE, I HAVE THESE FRIENDS OF MINE 
THE OTHER HALVES OF ME, WHO KEEP ME SANE IN TROUBLED TIMES 
AND WHEN I LOSE MY WAY, I HAVE THEM THERE IN THE BACK OF MY MIND 
AND THEN I DON'T FEEL LONELY AFTER ALL


A YEARS GONE BY AND WHAT WE HAD HAS CHANGED 
NO ONE SEEMS TO CARE FOR WHAT WE'D PERFECTLY ARRANGED 
I SCOUR OVER MEMORIES; I FEEL UNTIL I'M NUMB 
BUT I STILL CAN'T EXPLAIN HOW WE GOT HERE FROM WHERE WE'RE FROM 
AND NOW  
WHEN I FEEL ALONE 

WHEN I FEEL ALONE

WE'VE TURNED OUR BACKS ON ALL THE THINGS WE SAID WE LOVED 
CAUSE EVERYONE'S DECIDED THAT THIS ISNT WHAT IT WAS 
WELL NOBODY ASKED ME IF I THOUGHT WE'RE ALLOWED TO CHANGE 
MAYBE THAT'S BECAUSE IM THE ONLY ONE WHO'S STILL THE SAME 
AND NOW

 
I AM STILL ALONE WITH ALL THESE FRIENDS OF MINE 
THE OTHER HALVES OF ME WHO RAN AWAY IN TROUBLES 
AND NOW I FEEL THE SHAME OF HOLDING ONTO WHAT'S NO LONGER MINE 
MAYBE THINGS ARE DIFFERENT AFTER ALL 
AND I JUST NEVER SAW IT AT ALL
 

(SKIP notices a bottle of Blankson Brew sitting on the bleachers.)

SKIP
Who brought this?
 
JACK
Andy. He stole it from his Dad's fridge.
 
(SKIP picks up the bottle and takes a swig.)

 
SKIP
(sarcastic) Mmm... (reads the label) Blankson's Brew. This is quality. (offers Jack a sip) You want?
 
JACK

No thanks. You know I didn't have a single drop of alcohol this past year, and wonder of wonders I'm still sane.
 
SKIP
Yeah but you're gay. See what sobriety can do to you?
 
JACK
Dick.
 
SKIP

No, that's for you. (SKIP takes a swig.) This shit sucks!
 
(JACK laughs. He notices WILL's backpack sitting by the players bench) 

SKIP
Is that yours?
 

JACK
What?
 
SKIP
Over there on the bench.
  
JACK
No.
 

(SKIP walks over and opens up the backpack and takes out a journal)
 
What are you doing?
 
SKIP
Exploring. (reading) "Williamson Henry."
 

(WILL runs in)
 
WILL
Don't!
 
SKIP
What?
 
WILL

Just don't read that, all right?
 
SKIP
Why not?
 
(WILL grabs for it)
 
SKIP
Is this a diary?

 
WILL
No.
 
SKIP
What is it?
 
WILL
It's none of your business!

 
(WILL reaches for it. SKIP tosses it to JACK who is sitting on the bleachers. JACK reads)

WILL
Come on!
 
JACK
(reads) "His science teacher was a woman with so many neuroses, it was amazing they allowed her to teach kids at all."

 
WILL
Could you not?
 
JACK
"She taught 6th grade and had a pet rat named Bean, who smelled like a combination of kitty litter and old urine."
 
SKIP
Hey, I remember Bean!

 
WILL
Give it back!
 
JACK
(flipping through the notebook) Is this about us?
 
(SKIP snatches the notebook away from JACK)


SKIP
(to WILL) Read it!
 
WILL
No.

 SKIP

Well then, allow me!
 
WILL
Skip!
 
SKIP
"She had supple breasts..."

WILL

It doesn't say that. Give it back!
 
SKIP
Only if you promise to read it.
 
(ANDY enters. Silence as everyone stares)

ANDY
I left my bag.

 
SKIP
You're just in time. Will was going to read from his diary.

WILL
It's not a diary...
 
SKIP
(to ANDY) Come on!

 
(Silence)

Or not. (to WILL) Read!
 
WILL
I don't...
 

SKIP
Read!
 
WILL
Fine! But you have to promise that you won't make fun of it.
 
SKIP
Oh, we will. OK we WON'T.
 

WILL
I'm serious.
 
JACK
(sincerely) We won't.
 
SKIP
Read!

 
(WILL takes the notebook and begins to read)

WILL
"There was no reason why these four boys should have been friends. What tied them together was the fact that they were uncommon. They were the outcasts of their 6th grade class. Jackson Ritchie was incredibly small for his age and was constantly teased about it. Within the first week, he had been shoved into 4 lockers by the same group of 8th graders. Hopper Thomas was a military brat who had lived in 5 different states before the age of 12. The fact that he was the new kid and had a goofy first name didn't help."
 
JACK
Yeah, your parents weren't really thinking long term with that one, were they?
 

SKIP
I was named after my grandfather.
 
JACK
Your grandfather's name was Hopper?
 
SKIP
Norman Hopper.
 

JACK
Why didn't they just name you Norman?
 
SKIP
I don't know. Shut up!
 
JACK
Hey! Don't yell at me. You should be thanking us for giving you such a kick ass nickname.
 

SKIP
(sarcastic) Yeah, Skip, that's real great.
 
JACK
Anything's better then Hopper.
 
SKIP
Shut up! (to WILL) Keep going.

 
WILL
"Anderson Scott, on the other hand, seemed like a fairly normal kid. But, Andy had a slight problem. From a very young age Andy had a bladder problem. In short, Andy couldn't control his pee and he became the first 6th grader in the history of Walden Middle School to piss his pants."
 
ANDY
Take that out!
 
SKIP
No Will, keep it in. That's the best part!

 
WILL
"And Williamson Henry had trouble with his weight. He was both the shortest and heaviest kid in his class, and no one let him forget it. Until he met Skip, Jack and Andy." 
 
JACK
Awww.... fatty.
 
WILL
"What at first seemed like a last resort actually resulted in an unexpected brotherhood. No matter what happened, they always never had to be alone. Their friendship is the type that defines a person; the kind of connection that lasts a lifetime. Life seems to push you in a direction whether you choose it or not. Oddly enough, life turned them around so that they could find each other."

 
SKIP
That's it?
 
WILL
That's all I'm reading.
 
JACK
It's really good.

 
WILL
Thanks.
 
ANDY
I hate it! That shit isn't funny! I had serious health issues when I was a kid.
 
(JACK grabs the notebook from WILL)


SKIP
Andy! If you hadn't pissed all over yourself we never would've become friends. 
 
ANDY
True, but it's a story, can't you change it a little? Artistic likeness?
 
SKIP
License?
 

ANDY
Yeah that.
 
JACK
(reading the notebook) You wrote about football tryouts?
 
WILL
Yeah, a little bit.

 
SKIP
I can't believe we tried to play football.
 
JACK
I can't believe I tried to play football.
 
SKIP
(laughs) You were quite a sight in those pads. They looked like they were eating you. You know, the seniors used to call you Popeye.


 (They all laugh)

JACK
(to SKIP) Well what about you?
 
SKIP
What about me?

 
JACK
Your haircut? You looked like a GI Joe.
 
SKIP
Shut up! My dad made me. At least I had a better nickname then Andy.
 
ANDY
What are you talking about? They gave me a kick ass nickname. Conan the Barbarian!

 
SKIP
You know why they called you that though, right?
 
ANDY
Cause I was strong as shit.
 
SKIP
And dumb as shit.

 
ANDY
Fuck that! At least I made the team.
 
SKIP
(sarcastic) And you got all that playing time too.
 
ANDY

I was their secret weapon.
 
WILL
Yeah and that's the way they kept you.
 
ANDY
Look who's talking! You were so fat in high school that your belly came out from under your jersey.
 
WILL

Nah-uh.
 
ANDY
You were a fucking tub!
 
WILL
I was not!
 
ANDY

Uh, yes you were!
 
(SKIP and JACK laugh)

WILL
Whatever, that was baby fat!
 
ANDY
Dude that was not baby fat. That was fat fat. You came to school with like twenty Snack Packs a day. You looked like Chunk from The Goonies!

 
(They all laugh)

WILL
You guys suck!
 
SKIP
Truffle Shuffle, truffle shuffle...
 

JACK and ANDY
Truffle shuffle, truffle shuffle...
 
THE GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS
 
 ANDY
CHUNK!

SKIP

POPEYE THE SAILOR MAN

WILL
GI JOE

WILL and ANDY
THE AMERICAN HERO

JACK
AND CONAN 

THE BARBARIAN 
NOT O'BRIEN

WILL
LOOK 
WE ARE STILL THE BOYS 
FRESHMAN YEAR, WE WERE QUEER 

SORRY 
WE WERE "DIFFERENT" 
THAT WASN'T A GAY JOKE

JACK
YOU WEIGH THE SAME THAT YOU DID BACK THEN 
BUT YOU WERE FIVE FOOT FOUR, NOW YOU'RE FIVE FOOT TEN 

AND YOUR OLD FAT NOW HAS STRETCH MARKS

SKIP
LOOK WHO'S TALKING ABOUT BEING AN AWKWARD MESS 
YOU WERE SO GANGLY, YOUR ARMS JUST DANGLED 
THEY WRAPPED 'ROUND TWICE WHEN YOU FOLDED THEM 'CROSS YOUR CHEST

ANDY
AND I WAS STRONG


JACK
BUT YOU WERE DUMB

SKIP
STILL ARE

ANDY
SHUT UP

WILL

YOU ARE

ANDY
YOUR MOM!!

ALL (except ANDY)
SEE

ALL

MAN THIS BRINGS ME
BACK TO THOSE GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS

WILL
WHEN WE WOULD RUN FROM BULLIES

JACK
WHEN WE WOULD HIDE IN TRASH CANS

SKIP

WHEN ALL THEY WANTED TO DO
WAS PUT US IN ONE

ANDY
AND WE'D SAY WE HAD GIRLFRIENDS

WILL
BUT NOBODY COULD MEET THEM

JACK

CAUSE THEY WERE ONLINE

SKIP
AND PROBABLY MEN

ALL
MAN THIS BRINGS ME 
BACK TO THINGS I 
HAVENT THOUGHT ABOUT SINCE THOSE GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS


WILL
HEY 
WHAT ABOUT YOU 
MR. YOU-KNOW-WHO 
JUNIOR ROTC

SKIP

YEA THAT WAS ME 
IT WAS MY DAD'S PLAN, BUT I GOT SOMETHING OUT OF IT 
I COULD END YOUR LIFE WITH MY BARE HANDS

WILL
FUCK YOU, BRING IT ON

ANDY
WATCH OUT, ARE YOU NUTS?


JACK
DON'T FIGHT... COME ON GUYS

SKIP
YOU'RE MINE!

ALL
SEE, THIS IS WHAT THE GOOD OLD DAYS SHOULD BE LIKE

JACK

FOOTBALL IN THE LIGHTS

WILL
PIZZA EVERY NIGHT

ANDY
WILL'S MOM EVERY NIGHT

SKIP
OR STREET FIGHTER 2


ALL
ARE THE THINGS THAT REMIND ME OF YOU

WILL
YOU'RE FAT

ANDY
YOU'RE DUMB

JACK

YOU'RE HOT!

SKIP
YOU'RE GAY!

ANDY
YEA, BUT HE HASN'T ALWAYS BEEN THAT WAY

(awkward silence. WILL quickly breaks the tension)

WILL

GOOD OLD GLORY DAYS ALWAYS SEEM TO SAY GOODBYE

SKIP
AND THEY BECOME THE PAST TENSE THAT WE APPLY TO OUR LIVES

ANDY
GOOD OLD GLORY DAYS ARE ONLY GOOD WHILE YOU'RE THERE

JACK
BUT WHEN THEY'RE DONE, THEY'RE NOT AS FUN 

EVEN THOUGH YOU STILL DO CARE 
MAN I MISS THOSE...


SKIP
UGLY SCHOOL CLOTHES

ANDY
WILL'S BIG JEW NOSE


WILL
ANDY'S MOM'S PANTYHOSE

ANDY
Hey!

JACK
MAN I MISS THOSE

SKIP

HIGH SCHOOL DANCE WOES

ANDY
BATHROOM PEEP SHOWS

WILL
WATCHING US GROW

ALL
MAN I MISS THOSE 

GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE 
MAN I MISS THOSE 
GOOD OLD GLORY TYPE DAYS

(They all end up lying on the bleachers and grass)

SKIP
How many kids do you think have graduated from Sturmsville?
 

JACK
So many.
 
SKIP
That's not a number, Jack. (laughs) Think about it though. The number of kids who sat, just like we did, dreaming about their futures.
 
WILL

How many kids do you think have sat on these bleachers? (Will runs over to the bleachers and stands on the first row of seats) How many? Who sat here? (Will runs back to the third row and stands) Who sat here?

(The guys laugh)

WILL
No seriously! (beat) How many people have made out right where you're sitting? (Points to where Andy is sitting)

 
ANDY
(reads some writing on the bleachers) Apparently "Chris and Amanda"
 
WILL
See, like that! Who are they? Where are they now? We could probably never figure out who that was. We'd have to go through every single yearbook...even then there are probably a thousand Chris' and Amanda's.
 
ANDY

I wonder if Amanda is hot?
 
SKIP
I wonder if she even knows her name is out here.
 
ANDY
Do you think they can feel us thinking about her right now?
 
WILL

Can you feel it when somebody is thinking about you?
 
ANDY
I can feel someone looking when I'm picking my nose in the car...
 
SKIP
True! So true!
 
WILL

(Will is examining the field) Think about all this grass. How many blades of grass are out here, do you think? Staring at us, breathing the air we exhale, living because of us. Right now, our CO2 is becoming their oxygen. We live because of them too. We owe everything to this grass.
 
JACK
You're insane.
 
WILL
No, I just have a very vivid imagination.
 

JACK
(getting up) So are we gonna set these sprinklers off or not?
 
SKIP
We still don't know the password.
 
WILL
Did you guys check every closet?

 
SKIP
You didn't give us the keys.
 
WILL
Oh (he pulls the keys out of his jacket pocket) Sorry. (he hands the keys to SKIP)
 

SKIP
I'll go find it.
 
(SKIP starts to exit)

SKIP
(to ANDY and JACK) You guys wanna come with? (to JACK) Or...

 
(SKIP looks at JACK and nods)

JACK
No, it's okay.
 
WILL
Andy?
 

ANDY
(to WILL) It's cool.
 
SKIP
We got it. Let's go!
 
(SKIP and WILL exit. ANDY and JACK are left alone. There is a long silence. ANDY takes a pack of cigarettes out of his pocket. JACK stares at him. ANDY offers one to JACK)


JACK
No... thanks.
 
(ANDY lights a cigarette.)

When did you start that?

ANDY
A couple months ago.
 

JACK
Why?
 
ANDY
It's relaxing.
 
JACK
That's dumb.
 

ANDY
Thanks.
 
(JACK just stares at ANDY. ANDY feels the stare, and puts out the cigarette. He takes a big, deep swig of his beer, almost finishing it. JACK picks up the copy of Playboy that has been lying on the ground. He begins flipping through pages. He opens it up to the centerfold and examines it.)

JACK
Wow. She's hot.
 
(ANDY stares at him. Silence.)


Don't you think?

ANDY
She's all right.

JACK
She's better then all right, I think. (He examines the picture further) Except for this.
 

ANDY
What?

JACK
Look at that bush. It's like an untouched forest down there! I can't deal with that. You gotta do a little upkeep. You know, trim away some of the hedge...

ANDY
Come on.

JACK

What?

ANDY
I know you don't want to talk about that.

(Silence. JACK closes the magazine and tosses it back on the ground. Another long, awkward silence. ANDY opens his duffle bag and pulls out two bottles of beer.)

You want one of these?

JACK
(sighs) Sure.


(ANDY hands a bottle to JACK. They both take a couple of sips. JACK winces at the taste.)

JACK
Remember when we used to steal liquor from Will's Dad's cabinet?

ANDY
(ANDY cracks a smile) Yeah.

JACK

I'll never forget that time we got caught. Mr. Henry's face will forever be etched in my mind. I'll never forget it, I thought Will was gonna get strangled.

ANDY
I got in so much trouble for that too. I was grounded for like a month.

JACK
You were always grounded! You must have spent half of middle school in your room.
 
ANDY
I know! And I did the same shit you guys did. Like when we stole that sign from the Presbyterian Church on Marengo.

 
JACK
(laughing) "God Answers Knee Mail."
 
ANDY
Yeah! My mom took my car away. Wouldn't let me go out for three weeks. You guys weren't even punished!
 
JACK

I had to spend winter break doing inventory at my dad's store.
 
ANDY
Whoop-de-fucking-do! I had to baby sit Samantha every day!
 
JACK
She's so cute though.
 
ANDY

She's Satan.
 
JACK
She's your sister!
 
ANDY
She's a bitch!
 
JACK

She's six!
 
(ANDY shrugs and takes another sip of beer)

So... who's Beth?

ANDY
I'm sorry?

JACK

Beth?
 
ANDY
Oh, just a girl I've been...

JACK
Ah hah. How long?
 
ANDY

A few weeks.
 
JACK
How'd you meet?
 
ANDY
At the pool.
 
JACK

And she lives around here?
 
ANDY
Yeah. She went to Roosevelt.
 
JACK
Oh. So you spotted her across the deep end and it was love at first sight?
 
ANDY

Not quite.
 
JACK
What's she like?
 
ANDY
She's nice.
 
(Silence)


JACK
Wow, you must really think a lot of her.
 
ANDY
What do you want? She's cool, smart. Wants to teach elementary school. Like first graders. (long pause) And she's hot.
 
JACK

THAT's what I was waiting for!
 
(JACK and ANDY laugh. SKIP and WILL enter. SKIP is waving a sheet of paper in the air)

WILL
Look what we found!
 
JACK
You got it!

 
WILL
This is definitely it.
 
(They all rush over to the box.)

WILL
Hold on! Shouldn't we say something?
 

JACK
Like what?
 
WILL
I don't know. This is a pretty big moment. I don't want to jump right into it. (looks at SKIP) Skip?
 
SKIP

Don't look at me. I don't know what to say.
 
(JACK, SKIP, ANDY, and WILL - all look in the box and try to think of something to say.)

ANDY
I got it! It's been fun - let's get this shit done! (Proud of his rhyming abilities, he sticks his hand in the box.)
 
WILL
(Smacking Andy's hand out of the way) No - that sucked!

 
ANDY
Then you say it!
 
WILL
Fine - I will! (silence) So, here we are... our 2nd annual prank. (silence)
 

ANDY
Wow! No you're right, yours was much better.
 
WILL
I'm not done! So we're back together after one long lonely year apart and tonight we're going to make some history!
 
ANDY
Damn straight!
 

WILL
(to SKIP) The paper, my good man.
 
(SKIP hands the paper to WILL. WILL unlocks the box)

ANDY
We should have like a signature that we leave behind when we're done.
 

JACK
What do you mean?
 
ANDY
Like a sign. You know like when Zorro does that Z thing.
 
SKIP
We could call ourselves "Los Banditos."
 

ANDY
That'd be sick!
 
SKIP
And we could each have our own code name. (to ANDY) Like we could call you "Tonto."
 
ANDY

Yeah!

(JACK laughs)

ANDY
What? (SKIP laughs) What!?

WILL
Tonto means dumb in Spanish.


ANDY
Fuck that!

SKIP
And you guys can just call me El Guapo!

WILL
(dawning on him) Ohhhh! You two are still talking?

 
JACK
Yeah.

WILL
Is he your boyfriend?

JACK
I guess.
 

WILL
Is he cool? What is he like?
 
JACK
Yea he's great, why would I date him if he wasn't?
 
WILL
What does he look like? I'm picturing a big black guy for some reason...
 

JACK
(laughs) No, he's white.
 
WILL
And?
 
JACK
You guys don't want to hear this.

 
SKIP
Sure we do.
 
WILL
Is he a good kisser?
 
ANDY
Jesus Christ!

 
JACK
I'm sorry.
 
SKIP
(to ANDY) What? What's your problem?
 
ANDY

I just don't wanna hear about this. Is that all right?
 
SKIP
No, actually it's not.
 
WILL
Skip?
 
SKIP

Will? (silence. To ANDY) What Andy?
 
ANDY
Nothing. Just forget it.
 
SKIP
No!

 
ANDY
Listen, I think I've been doing a pretty good job of staying quiet...
 
SKIP
Staying quiet? What, do you want some kind of award for that?
 
JACK
Skip, enough.

 
SKIP
No! He's said some shitty things to you tonight and I wanna know why. (to ANDY) Is it going to be like this every time we hang out? Do we have to treat it like it's some big secret! He's GAY, Andy, get used to it.
 
ANDY
That's not the point! I just -
 

SKIP
What, Andy?
 
OTHER HUMAN BEINGS (REPRISE) 

SKIP
 THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS YOU NEVER DO
 

JACK
Don't, Skip.
 
SKIP
TO OTHER HUMAN BEINGS
 
ANDY
I don't have to listen to this. (ANDY grabs his bag and starts putting the rest of the beers inside)


SKIP
LIKE PUSH AWAY YOUR FRIENDS 
FOR NO REAL REASON AT ALL
 
ANDY
Fuck you!

SKIP

BECAUSE WE HAVE THE ABILITY TO CHOOSE 
WHAT WE MAKE A PERSON FEEL
 
ANDY
What about me, Skip?
 
SKIP
AND TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR WHO YOU LOSE 

WHEN THE PAIN YOU INFLICT BECOMES REAL

 ANDY
I'm supposed to be your friend too!
 
SKIP
ANDY 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY 

IS HE MAKES THE PROBLEMS 
AND WON'T TRY TO SOLVE THEM

(ANDY turns around)

CAN'T CHANGE ME

ANDY
YOU THINK YOU KNOW WHY 

IM ACTING THE WAY I AM 
CEPT ALL YOU SEE'S THE OUTSIDE OF ME 
YOU THINK THAT I HIDE 
THAT I DON'T KNOW WHO I AM 
BECAUSE YOU THINK YOU'RE SMARTER THAN ME

YOU DON'T THINK I CARE 

BUT THAT'S NOT FAIR 
ALL I DO IS CARE 
BUT DOES ANYBODY CARE ABOUT ME?

SKIP
ANDY 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY


ANDY
IS HE HAS HIS FEELINGS  
AND NO ONE ACCEPTS THEM 
AND ANDY 
THE THING ABOUT ANDY  
IS HE IS ALLOWED TO  

FEEL HOW HE WANTS TO

YOU MAY NOT AGREE, BUT IM THE ONE WHO'S HURT, SO IT'S NOT YOUR CHOICE 
YOU LIED TO ME ABOUT WHO YOU SAID YOU WERE, SO YOU LOST YOUR VOICE 
BUT YOU STILL TELL ME THIS IS ALL MY FAULT 
CAUSE YOU GUYS LIKE PRETENDING YOU'RE ADULTS

ALL OF YOU 

I KNOW ITS FUCKED UP BUT SO AM I 
I GUESS ITS TRUE 
THAT ONCE YOU'VE CHANGED, THERE ARE NO GOODBYES 
TO THE OLD YOU 
THE OLD YOU

YOU CANT CHANGE ME 

IM WHO ILL BE FOREVER AND EVER 
ITS WHO I SAID ID BE 
SO YOU CAN ALL DECIDE 
IM NOT JUSTIFIED 
BUT YOU CANT CHANGE ME 
AND ILL NEVER BE WHAT YOU WANT ME TO BE 

ALL I AM IS ME

(ANDY starts to leave. JACK stops him)

JACK
Andy, don't go. We need to talk about this!
 
ANDY
No. Just leave me alone.
 

(ANDY exits)

JACK
Should I go after him?
 
SKIP
What are you gonna say?
 
JACK

I dunno...I'm sorry?
 
SKIP
For what? He's the one that's being...
 
JACK
Being what, Skip? He was right! He reacted the way he felt and -
 
SKIP

No, fuck that! That doesn't make it right.
 
JACK
You said give him time to cool off. And you jumped all over him.
 
SKIP
So? I'm not gonna let him talk to you like that!
 
JACK

Skip, I can take care of myself. I don't need you fighting my battles.
 
SKIP
So it's my fault for yelling at him?
 
JACK
I didn't say that.
 
SKIP

Then what!? If he can't accept that this is the way things are then fuck him. Let him go! Maybe it's better.
 
WILL
What do you mean?
 
SKIP
Without him. I'm saying, maybe it's better that he left.
 
(Silence)


THINGS ARE DIFFERENT (REPRISE)

JACK
THINGS ARE DIFFERENT 
THINGS HAVE CHANGED 
IT MAY BE BETTER THIS WAY 
BUT IT'S STILL STRANGE


NOW, IT'S JUST YOU AND ME AND WILL 
ONE TWO AND THREE

JACK, SKIP AND WILL
NOT FOUR ANYMORE

(The sound and lights of a car pulling out of the parking lot.)

SKIP

Well this is great. Some fucking friends we are.
 
(Another long silence)

SKIP
I'm gonna go. Do you guys want a ride?
 
JACK
We're not gonna finish?

 
SKIP
You want to?
 
JACK
Not really.
 
WILL
You never did.

 
(SKIP and JACK begin to exit.)

SKIP
You coming?
 
WILL
That's okay.
 

SKIP
Come on.
 
WILL
No...I think I'm gonna stay out here a little longer.
 
SKIP
Okay. (looks around) Goodnight, man.

 
WILL
Night, guys.
 
JACK
Hey, I'll give you a call tomorrow. Maybe the three of us can see a movie or something?
 
WILL
Maybe.

 
JACK
Yea maybe. Well...I'll call you.
 
SKIP
Night man.
 
(SKIP and JACK exit. WILL crumples up the paper with the password and sits down on the bleachers.)


TURN AROUND
 
 WILL
FOR SOME REASON "THREE" SOUNDS A LITTLE BIT EMPTY 
FOR SOME REASON "FOUR" HAD A NICER RING 
FOR SOME REASON WE COULDN'T HOLD ON TO EACH OTHER 
BECAUSE OF OUR DIFFERENCES IN THINGS


FOR SOME REASON I DON'T THINK IT'S REALLY OVER 
FOR SOME REASON THIS ENDING SEEMS TOO CLEAN 
FOR SOME REASON, WE EVER MET IN THE FIRST PLACE 
AND I THINK THAT REMAINS TO BE SEEN

WE USED TO SNEAK OUT LATE 
TO STAND WHERE I AM NOW 

LIKE WE'D NEVER GO AWAY

LITTLE DID I KNOW 
I'D BE BACK OUT HERE NOW 
IN SUCH A DIFFERENT PLACE 
JUST AT THE SAME TIME OF DAY

TURN AROUND 

FACE THE FACT THAT YOU DON'T KNOW HOW TO REACT 
BUT TURN AROUND 
TURN AROUND AND YOU JUST MIGHT BE FOUND

TURN AROUND  
TURN AWAY AND TRY TO SAY THAT IT'S OKAY 
TO TURN AROUND 

TURN AROUND AND YOU JUST MIGHT BE FOUND

(WILL opens up his notebook and reads.)

"Will had been grounded for the last two weeks of his summer vacation. As he sat alone in his room, an unexpected knock came from the second story window. He turned around to see Andy's smiling face hovering outside. Will looked down to see Skip and Jack struggling to support Andy's legs. Andy tried to say something but quickly lost his grip and plummeted to the ground. They all landed in a heap, laughing and hopelessly trying to untangle themselves. Will smiled. He was only 13, but he knew the idiots on his front lawn were the brothers he never had."

THIS WILL ALWAYS BE HOME 
WHERE WE DREAMED UNDER THESE SAME STARS 
WE CAN ALWAYS COME HOME 

TO RECLAIM WHAT ONCE WAS OURS 
THIS IS OUR HOME 
WITH MEMORIES FROM A LIFETIME AGO 
THAT ONLY SEEM TO SHOW

THAT I SHOULD TURN AROUND 
AND TURN AWAY FROM WHAT HAD BROUGHT ME HERE TODAY 

TURN AROUND  
AND MAYBE THEN I'LL BE FOUND AGAIN

(The sprinkler system goes off, soaking WILL. WILL just sits on the bench. He closes the notebook. Blackout.)

THE END





